People... Jebediah is no longer with us.
But we haven't lost anyone else.
And that's something to cheer for.
I'm so excited for this.
This is gonna be epic.
Because we're landing on the moon today.
At least I'm gonna try.
Ah, we'll do it, we'll do it.
No problem.
Oh... Man.
Feels good to be in front of the computer.
What about the test?
Well, I went to see the doctor.
And she's like, yeah, you probably have ADHD.
And I'm gonna have a follow-up conversation now.
She saw enough to, you know, determine another conversation was needed.
So we'll see.
She said, you have definite signs, is what she said.
Thank you for asking.
We choose to go to the moon!
Yes, we do.
Did this not already happen back when you played Subnautica?
It did.
But that was a different doctor in a different city.
And they asked me, well...
Are you fine?
Like, is it okay?
And I'm like, yeah, I feel good.
Alright, guess we probably don't need to do anything about it.
You know?
But I don't know.
I feel like I have trouble focusing.
Lately I've been noticing some things.
I don't know.
So I went to get another opinion.
Okay, man.
Are you ready for some Kerbal Space Program?
There we go.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Space Program and Kerbal Space Program.
I'm actually going to delete my old savior.
We don't need it anymore.
There we go.
Oh, wait.
You can't even see.
Not that it matters.
Guys, I'm just going to play it from the waiting menu here.
So you can't see anything.
You're just going to have to listen.
Okay?
And imagine what I'm doing.
Nah, I would never do that.
Come on.
Never would I do such a thing.
I'm drinking a Foxy Condi Lemon.
It's quite good.
Thank you for asking.
It's the Zero Sugar variant.
It's a new one.
It's quite good.
Truly a blind playthrough.
Not for me, but for you.
Exactly.
I also went to see the new Resident Evil movie.
Although I only saw the first Resident Evil movie of all the Resident Evil movies.
So I don't really know how the rest of the movies are.
But this one was good.
I recommend it.
That was a fun experience.
That was a nice one.
Highly recommend.
It was fun.
Okay.
I am going to shut this down.
We're about to play some Kerbal Space Program.
And hopefully get far.
We'll see.
Reputation is 0%?
Are you kidding me?
Me who spin around the moon?
Come on, bro.
I can't believe that.
Okay.
I finally got a proper Dark Mode mod now.
Something that I actually like the way it looks.
I also added another cool thing related to parachutes.
You'll see what that is when we get to it.
Actually, you know what?
I'm having a blast just modding the shit out of this game, you know?
Like, I feel like this mod is one of the- or this game is one of the few that really benefit from mods.
And a lot of them.
Let's see here.
What was I doing?
So we have 200,000 in the bank.
That's pretty damn good.
32.6 science.
There was something I wanted to get here.
Was it that one?
No.
Maybe it was.
Space Exploration.
Oh, this one probably.
I forgot.
I was saving for something.
I think this is the last one I got.
Maybe General Construction.
I don't remember.
In any case, we should just go do some science.
Oh, I also added more music to the game, by the way.
Some more space music.
Just to add some variety.
You know, I'm modding the shit out of this, man.
I'm having a blast.
Let me warp to Sunrise.
Let's see the contracts.
So we have science data from space around Kerbin.
How did I not do that one?
Expires in four years.
Okay, dude.
Wait, I wonder if these change every time I log in.
I don't remember what I had last time.
Explore the moon.
We have enough data on the moon to attempt a landing.
Or we could stage one.
It's up to you.
Nice.
Ah, man.
I don't want to get punched in the face by an astronaut, you know?
Maybe I shouldn't claim that it was staged.
Man, who's the one who did that?
It wasn't Neil Armstrong.
It was the other guy.
I forget his name now.
Temperature surveys of the moon.
Maybe that's a little too hasty.
Rescue Sherlo from orbit of Kerbin.
I mean, that's a lot of money.
It is.
But we need science, so I feel like we should go to the moon.
We need some new areas to, you know, perform science in.
Oh, I remember now what I wanted to get from this.
It was science related.
Was it that one?
That one.
EVA experiments kit.
This is the one we're getting.
90 science required.
Okay.
Let's just make a rocket here and go to the moon.
We are gonna go straight ahead and land on the moon.
So, with that said, maybe we should do, like, multiple contracts?
So, also, look at this one.
Bring Moonstone back with you.
Damn.
Conduct temperature surveys.
So, we already have one, like, around Kerbin.
Maybe I should do that one first.
Before anything else.
We could combine it with this.
Go rescue Sherlo.
And then when we have those two done, boom.
Then we go home.
And then we go to the moon.
I even have the vessel saved.
The crew.
If you remember.
Kerbal rescue unit.
Let's do it, man.
Yep.
We're doing those two.
And then we're going to the moon after.
Okay.
Let's see here.
That's the crew.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Look at that.
It's a beaut, Clark.
Was there any, like, drawbacks to this one?
Wait, Carson.
That's the new guy.
Hmm.
Wait, he's already level one.
Sweet.
I guess we can let Carson have a stab at this.
What about the engineer?
Increase resource converter efficiency.
I don't know what that means.
Drill efficiency.
Oh, man.
Are we gonna get...
What's his name?
Fucking hell.
The guy from Die Hard, you know?
Armageddon dude.
Are we gonna get him and his team of drillers?
To an asteroid?
Why am I blanking on his name?
Uh, so wait.
We gotta do science, right?
Haven't I already done all the science I can do?
What if I bring home, like, an empty report?
Will that count?
I guess we'll find out.
I could also try to, uh, transmit.
I've never done that.
Let's try that.
So, that would be that one.
Let's add a little antenna to this.
Oh, god.
How was it?
Uh.
There we go.
Maybe we add...
Maybe one here.
That's cool, right?
Looks a little weird.
That's alright.
Now, this one...
I think this one had a lot of Delta V.
Actually, we can just add more.
So, right now we have a swivel.
That's the one that can gimbal.
Oh, we even have this one.
An extra little stage.
I guess that's fine.
Now, this part here, maybe we can add a little bit more.
We have this one now.
Maybe that's overkill, though.
Not sure.
What I could do is add one more fuel tank.
Just to have, like, a little extra, right?
Make it look nice.
Uh, white.
And then we add an engine.
It actually just...
Oh, there it is.
Okay.
So, this one first.
How much, uh...
Thrust to wait?
Okay.
That one.
This one.
And these two.
Oh, we have to separate this.
Ah!
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
We need the, uh...
We need these ones to deploy first.
Yep.
And then the big ones after.
Nice.
I think I'm ready.
The mission is to get into, uh...
Carbon orbit.
We're gonna rescue...
Shermo, or whatever his name was.
We're gonna get science.
We're gonna try and transmit the science.
And then we're gonna transmit Sherbo.
Or Shermo, whatever.
Save it.
I'm just gonna send him...
You know, into the Communitron thingy.
Okay.
Here we go.
The first launch.
I also fixed a little problem with the flags.
So now they don't flicker anymore.
While still having my beloved...
Temporal anti-aliasing.
So that's nice.
Okay, let me see here.
Oh, maybe...
Oh, dude, dude, dude, dude.
Maybe I should have checked beforehand.
Where this guy is.
Oh, shit.
Actually, uh...
Sherlock.
Target.
Dude, I should have waited...
Until, uh...
Until he's, like, close.
Last time I did this, I got a little lucky...
That he was just, you know...
Right next to me when I came up there.
Okay, I'm trying to turn as much as I can...
But of course we cannot until this stage.
Now we can start turning slightly.
This will be the most beautiful orbit...
You've ever seen.
Uh-oh.
I can feel it wants to really tip to the right now.
Please don't tip.
Okay.
I need to check my...
Oh, I can do that here.
Okay.
So Apoapsis is 18 kilometers right now.
So we have to go way further up.
We may have to activate the little engine...
Just to get us a little higher up here.
That's probably fine.
Yeah, look.
We're only getting to, like, 34.
Maybe I should have taken the other booster.
Bye-bye.
Yeah, it's...
Oh, man.
This is not looking good, man.
I fucked this up.
This is a bad launch.
Terrible launch.
Wasting a lot of fuel just to get...
Up here.
From the last stage I have.
I mean, okay.
We're making...
We're also adding a lot of horizontal speed right now, so...
Or velocity, I guess.
And there is a difference, people.
60 kilometers.
We're gonna wait until we're at 70 at least.
Because then we're out of the atmosphere.
Maybe I'll even turn it slightly more.
Imagine doing, like, one continuous burn from the surface and all the way into orbit.
That's crazy.
Stop.
Let's have a look.
Where's my guy?
He's back there.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I actually like this.
Actually, I don't like it.
I hate it.
Um, more.
I'm wasting a lot of fuel here!
This is not good, actually.
No, no, no.
Stop, no, stop, stop, stop.
We're gonna have to do it up here.
So we have one minute, 13 seconds until we reach that.
And we're at 1500 meters per second.
And with this engine, we burn very slowly.
So...
Maybe, like, 40 seconds burn or so.
Give or take.
Can I align it here?
Okay.
Fast forward just slightly.
Maybe I'll start now.
Go!
Let's have a look.
Okay, we only burned half, actually.
It's a lot.
Oh, man.
I should have added the big booster.
In hindsight, that would have been so much better.
Why didn't I do it?
Massive mistake.
It's looking good.
1900?
I think it's, like, 2300 we need.
Oh, I have to watch these.
That's right.
And let's not forget about the science.
Here we go.
Periapsis.
It's coming out.
Boom.
Maybe even add...
No, okay, that's fine.
Okay, we're in orbit.
We made it.
Yeah, 2300.
Okay, now.
Oh, man.
The fuel is bad.
We may have to settle with just the science on this one.
I hate to say it.
What is your name?
Sherlow.
Sherlow, I'm sorry, but we may have to...
You know.
What's the word?
Postpone your rescue.
Intersect one.
We are separated 255 kilometers.
That's not good.
We don't have enough fuel for that.
Let's try the science communication thing.
Oh, right.
It's because he's in here.
Okay, so we're in space.
What if I were to do this?
No usable in-range...
What?
Do I need to...
Oh, transmit data.
Unable to transmit.
What?
Is it because we don't have, like, a connection with something?
Wait, crew report?
No, wait.
Let me go do an EVA.
I'm gonna do EVA report.
Hey, look!
4.8 science, so we haven't done this.
You think you see something moving on the moon's surface.
You're officially terrified.
Wait, what?
How are you seeing the moon from here?
There's no way you're seeing shit, especially not with the sun right next to it.
Liar.
This guy just falsified a report.
I can't believe it.
Get back in.
Now, let's try and transmit.
Unable to transmit?
Why?
Antenna rating 500k.
Why can't I do that?
Wait, wait, wait.
Let me review data.
Okay, let's just keep...
Actually, yeah.
So, it doesn't matter.
We don't need to transmit anyway.
We just gotta get home with the science and we're Gucci.
Right?
I'm sorry, Sherlo.
I'm gonna get you next time.
I just don't have the fuel for this.
I need the big booster.
Is Sherlo a guy or a...
female?
I feel like that name could be either.
Okay, let's splash down in the ocean.
And then I gotta show you guys something cool.
Also, listen.
New music.
I added some various space music.
We're gonna burn retrograde here.
SAS.
Actually, we don't need that yet.
There we go.
Actually, sometimes it's easier to have SAS off.
Maneuver to where you wanna go and then just press it to have it stabilize on the point you're at, you know?
Because when you have SAS on and you try to move something, it's like...
It's wanting to resist your movement, you know what I mean?
Whereas if you do that...
Better.
That should do it.
Yep.
Ah, but I do not wanna splash down on the dark side.
Let's just...
Burn a little crazy here.
That should do it.
So now we have to...
God, I wish I could actually just get rid of this.
Because we don't need the shaker setup right now.
Because we don't have somebody with us.
Dang.
Looking good, though.
Retrograde.
Also, something I'm not quite understanding here.
You can switch between surface and target.
Oh, wait.
Target?
Oh.
No.
Surface and orbit.
It feels more accurate to be in the surface orientation when you're coming down.
At least with, like, the heat shield.
So it makes more sense to be like that, I think.
Right now they seem to be the same, but, you know.
And why isn't this antenna working?
Oh!
There we go!
Transmitted!
Done!
We did that one!
Perfect!
Okay, so is it because we are now?
Ah, look!
We have a connection to whatever this is.
It's probably like a little dish down there.
Ah!
That is so cool!
Very nice.
I was like, maybe I'm missing something like a battery or whatever.
But no, it seems like you can just do that.
Cool.
Whoa, don't go too fast now.
Actually, you can go a little faster.
We're not even that fast.
This is an easy approach.
Carson, are you excited?
He's excited.
I have it on X4 right now.
Maybe it's a mistake.
I don't know.
When you do this enough times, you know.
You just want to...
get to the surface quick.
I swear, like...
these views are like half the game for me.
Going somewhere and just...
looking at where you are and what you've done, you know.
It's...
never gets old, man.
So good.
Love these re-entries here.
I'm gonna speed up.
Hopefully nothing's gonna mess me up.
We are slowing down quite a bit.
Yeah, perfect, perfect.
Looking good.
Very nice.
Oh god, it's so beautiful.
Holy shit, man.
I can't believe, like, these clouds are a mod you can download.
Like, what the fuck?
That's insane.
Insane modding skills.
From whoever did that.
Oh, uh...
Parachutes!
Let's not forget.
I have four parachutes now.
On this one.
Because it's like...
a double pod setup.
DPS.
I can speed up a bit more here.
That's fine.
Whoa, whoa!
Oh, that was my booster stage or whatever.
That thing is gone now.
Whoa.
Ah, we're upside down now.
Last time it was fine.
Like, we hit it with this pointy end and it was actually no problem.
I thought it would definitely break or something because it looks brittle, you know?
The next mission, we're just gonna go for the rescue.
We're not gonna try any science.
We're just gonna get a bunch of Delta Vs so we have lots of playroom.
Here we go.
Carson, you are officially on the planet.
Holy shit.
Beautiful.
Look at that.
Recover.
Okay.
How much did I get for that?
Is it actually in order?
Ah, whatever.
I had like two...
No, I had 190.
So I got like 30,000 or so.
Okay, so...
When I go rescue this guy...
Is there anything...
Oh, wait.
Rescue Harster?
Maybe I take two rescues at the same time.
Ah, but wait, wait.
Then we need a double shaker.
We can't do a double shaker.
That's way too crazy.
How about we stick with one shaker?
And I call it a shaker now.
Whatever.
That's not what it is.
It's the mixing thing.
No, it's the measuring thing.
Fuck it.
You know what I mean.
Okay.
Time for the kickback.
That's a lot.
I think this will do it.
Like, this is all I need.
Oh, wait.
Let's not forget.
We also have this stuff now.
Can I do something funky with that?
So we have this.
Look.
I feel like we should do something with that.
Now that we're rich.
Okay.
Let's do a quick redesign.
This is the crew two.
Save.
This is the second variety.
We're gonna completely re-envision this.
Let's just get rid of everything.
Let's do this.
I wanna make it thick.
And...
I guess this one?
Ooh.
Yo, it's starting to look like a funky shape here.
Man, you...
Those are some thin tanks.
I'll turn them all white.
Wait, let me see if my engines actually fit.
So this is a new one.
Ooh, that one fits.
Skipper.
I think that one's too large.
Yeah.
Poodle.
Also too large.
Unless...
Wait.
We could do a skipper, but watch this.
Ah, damn.
No.
There's also this one.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait a minute.
We have new shit?
Give me that one.
Oh!
Okay, wait.
Fuck this one then.
Actually, no.
Keep it.
No.
Wait.
Hmm.
Let me think.
Dude.
We're gonna make like a crazy shape here.
Um...
Okay, first things first.
Let's look at what engine I wanna use up there.
So this one has...
310 in VAC, ISP.
320.
Doesn't say.
350.
And this one...
3...
Oh my god.
So this one is actually as good as that one.
Almost.
But it's much smaller.
But of course that also means you have to burn for longer, right?
This one has...
Uh...
60 kilonewtons in space.
This one has 250.
Ooh...
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Let me...
Let me do, uh...
We're gonna get rid of that.
We're gonna do that.
Maybe I'll even add more.
Tell me I have a bigger one.
How...
Okay, how come I can't see the radius of it, though?
I don't know how big this is.
Rockomax...
I mean, I assume it's like categorized, so these three belong together, and then these three?
Let me try that one.
Yes!
And now?
Oh my god, it looks so sexy.
It looks like a little fat, chubby rocket, doesn't it?
With a funky head.
Hmm.
I gotta be honest, this looks terrible.
I don't know what I've done here.
I don't like the look of it.
Hmm.
Also, it's already 7,000 just for this part.
Uh...
Maybe we don't need all that.
Let me think.
Maybe I should buy all of these, just to have them, you know?
Look at this fuel tank, it's like all spiky.
What's up with that?
And this one.
I wish I could sort of tell how big this upper part is.
Oh, wait a second.
Oh!
Wait.
That works?
Oh, never mind then.
I was like, okay, I don't have something that fits.
No way.
That looks goofy as hell.
That doesn't look right.
Okay, you know what?
No.
Fuck all this.
We're gonna experiment with that later.
I don't like it at all now.
The fact that that doesn't fit makes me highly uncomfortable.
We're going back to the old design, but better this time.
So, that one.
Then we're gonna add the engine.
The terrier engine.
And look how beautiful that is.
I think it's pretty.
Oh, yeah.
Look at that one.
All black.
Then we add this guy.
And now...
Ooh!
I know what we're gonna do.
I know.
This is so good.
We're gonna add...
One of these.
A...
I guess...
Swivel?
And then we're gonna add the ones on the side here.
Okay?
Like that.
And...
The question now is...
Which one do I use?
20...
Thousand...
No.
2,500.
And if I take...
Wait, what a...
Oh...
Oh my god!
Wait.
Ha ha ha!
Uh...
20,000 just for this rocket!
I feel like these boosters may be a little too big.
Huh?
I think that's overdoing it.
I even feel like this one is overdoing it.
Like...
Look how...
It's taller than the fucking rocket itself!
Nah, we're gonna go with this, I guess.
2,500.
But that's not even that much more than what I had before.
I guess I could add more than two.
No, actually, let's just go with the big ones.
3,000!
Not bad.
Well, why is it so close?
Also, you know what I should do?
Let's add more of these.
Just so...
You know, more structural support here.
You see?
Then we do two of these.
It's so finicky, the way this...
I can't hit it.
There we go.
Oh, there we go.
But they're a little too high.
Let me actually do...
No.
Uh...
Move.
It's taller than the rocket!
Oh, man.
Okay, you know what?
I really want to do this sort of sideways decoupling motion.
It's just not a good idea.
We're going with the pencil.
I wish I wouldn't have to do that.
But I have to.
It's too much.
And look at this.
It has almost the same delta V, too.
The extra mass before it almost did nothing.
That's crazy, right?
Now we need some aerodynamicity.
I'm gonna add that at the...
Let me see here.
Here.
Four of them.
Pretty.
Now we're gonna move it up a little bit.
The signing rockets is so much fun.
While it may be a little finicky and janky to do, the absolute, uh...
You know...
Choices you have and the feeling of it is amazing.
Right?
Okay, let's just double-check everything before we go.
Big booster.
This one.
That one.
They go together.
This one.
That one.
And then we have...
The drogues.
And the normal.
Okay.
And pilot.
Carson.
So Carson got rescued last time.
He's now going to rescue...
Uh, the new guy.
Sherlock.
Uh...
Maybe I should wait until he's close now.
Let me see.
I guess I need to track.
So where am I launching from?
It's like here, right?
And this guy is...
Dude, we still have Carson's debris and stuff here.
Wait, vessel?
Who the hell is that?
Wait.
What is this?
Oh, I forgot about Valentina!
Holy fuck!
I totally forgot about you!
I am so...
I'm so sorry.
Guys, I have completely forgotten that this happened.
That's right!
She got, uh...
Left behind up here.
That's messed up.
Valentina, I'm coming for you soon.
It's gonna be good.
So let me see here.
If the space center is...
Where's the space center?
Is that the space center there?
Oh, it is.
Okay.
So the space center's there.
Oh, wait!
Valentina's here!
They're both here now!
Wait, no.
Oh, I see.
It's on the other side of the...
Okay, okay, I see.
It's on the other side.
Let's fast forward a bit.
Dude, they're both gonna be sort of close to each other now.
I feel like we should prioritize getting Valentina home.
Then again, she is experienced space flighter.
So maybe it's okay if she can stay up here just a little longer.
Okay, so we're here now?
I wonder what the good time is to do it.
So maybe we wait until we're like here.
I guess let me see how fast I'm moving.
Yeah, I would say that works.
So we're gonna go to here.
Maybe a little more like that.
Okay.
Valentina, I'll be back for you.
Be safe.
I'm coming for both of you.
But, I mean, not at the same time, of course, because the shaker only supports one.
Thus is the limitation of the shaker.
We need the crew too.
There it is.
Okay, here we go.
Launch time.
Wish me luck.
I actually really love these rescue missions.
There's something about it that's so cool.
Oh, that's a tall boy.
Here we go.
Oh, yeah.
It's even lifting off, I think, faster than the other boost that we had.
Even though it's bigger.
And that's more mass.
It just has a lot more stuff flowing out per second.
Could be wrong.
Let's have a look here.
Oh, I'm coming for you.
I'm actually not sure who I should prioritize here.
I'm undecided.
Maybe the one who I will naturally get closest to is the one I'll rescue.
That sounds right, doesn't it?
Have a look around.
So pretty.
Oh, a shadow is over there, look.
That's funny.
Okay, so I'm going to start turning.
Oh, well, I can't, I guess.
Not yet.
But very soon I'll start turning.
This is a very late turn.
Can't really do much about it.
Now we turn.
I need to click on here.
So I need to see what height they're at.
75-ish.
So right at the edge of space.
We're actually almost there on apoapses.
I'm going to start turning a little more horizontal then.
Maybe like here.
Let's see.
Look at this, we're coming in right between them.
This is sick.
More horizontal.
Yes.
Oh, we're going to be there.
Actually, let me try and target him.
But I guess we need to get into orbit no matter what here.
This is a necessity.
Trying to keep apoapses kind of stable now.
Yeah.
Not bad.
This is definitely so much easier now with the big engine.
Or the booster compared to the other one we had.
Looking good.
Goodbye.
Thank you for your service.
Are you ready?
We're going to wait.
Until.
So one minute.
And we are at 1000.
Okay, that's going to take a long time.
I feel like that's almost like a minute burn.
You know?
So maybe we start burning in like 10 seconds or so.
Oh, they're a little ahead of me now.
We can do it.
Look at our stage.
Bye-bye.
Dude, look at us being exactly in between them right now.
Maybe I'll turn a little bit more horizontal.
Wait a minute.
We are meshing via target here.
Let's keep it on orbit for now just to see.
It's looking good.
I'm going to catch up to Valentina.
Very soon.
Apoapses is stable.
Weirdly stable.
Okay, let's have a look at the...
Circle here.
Apoapses coming up.
Not even half-fueled yet.
Oh, that's good.
That's good.
That's very good.
There we go.
Oh, we already have a...
Kind of an encounter here.
And my target right now is who?
Velocity, altitude, distance.
Okay, so this is my target.
Let me burn a little more.
What if I target you?
Okay, so there's like an intersect over there.
And one here.
And just burn a bit.
It's kind of hard to tell which orbit I'm in.
There's so much space debris that I've made up here.
I can't see shit.
In any case, I think we just need to wait a little bit.
Sherlock.
We're kind of close over here.
120 kilometers is not that bad.
We could definitely burn that.
Let's just fast forward slightly.
We're actually kind of far.
He's going to be here.
I'm going to be there.
Oh, this is a tough one.
The good news is we have a lot of fuel to play with here.
And we have the choice between two targets.
So we are in a slightly lower orbit than Valentina.
So we should catch up to her eventually.
Then again, we are a little higher over here.
So maybe the trick is to burn a little retrograde right now.
Just to bring that down a bit.
Oh, look at that.
Something appeared.
I also feel like the inclination is not quite right here between us.
That's another problem.
I don't want to get the periapsis below 70.
Okay, 92 kilometers.
I feel like we can work with that.
When we get there, we just got to start burning towards the target.
Trust.
And we currently have who selected?
It's not...
Oh, wait.
That's Carson.
Wait, Carson's debris.
Oh!
This is the trash that my current pilot left behind last time he was in orbit.
Good job.
Sure low.
Okay, so we're going for...
Let me actually just test Valentina again.
This is going to be...
How many kilometers?
150.
Yeah, that's not good.
I like, uh...
I like Sherlock.
I think Valentina's going to stay here a little longer.
We could maybe try and catch up even more here.
If we burn retrograde just slightly...
Should be in a lower orbit.
Right?
And then we approach.
See that?
And...
Boom!
Look at that!
1.2 kilometers!
The problem is, though...
We have a periapsis of 52, so we're going to be...
Skirting through the atmosphere slightly on our way there.
Which means we're going to slow down.
Which means it's not going to be 1.2.
It's going to be something like 5.
I'm going to guesstimate.
Let's see.
Let me actually target the other one now that we burned a bit.
Just to see the difference.
Not looking good on Valentina.
It's gotta be Sherlock.
Even now, we did something.
Separation is even more now.
Maybe one of us is inside the atmosphere?
Oh!
0.7 kilometers now!
Holy shit!
Even better.
Also, I was looking at the wrong intersect, I think.
Okay.
We gotta let Jesus take the wheel here.
We're gonna go through the atmosphere.
Trust it'll be fine.
Here we go.
We're gonna get down to 52-ish on periapsis.
It's gonna be even lower because we're slowing down.
Oh, wait.
Shit.
Uh-oh.
We may act...
This is actually a problem.
I just realized.
We may actually start to speed up so much.
Or sorry.
Slow down.
That we burn up or not burn up.
But we're gonna fall through the atmosphere.
Nah.
No way.
We're at 2,300.
Nah.
We're gonna...
We're gonna get through.
Watch.
It's gonna take a while.
We can't really fast-forward faster right now.
It is what it is.
I almost don't want to look at the craft.
I just want to see the map.
Oh!
Scary.
23 minutes since launch.
Feels like a lot more, doesn't it?
With all the time-forwarding we've done here.
But I guess we are orbiting quite fast.
It's a small planet.
It's not quite Earth-sized.
Oh!
Periopsis is now 51.
Not good.
And look at this.
We're already drifting over here on the intersect.
Nine co- Oh!
Look at how fast that is changing.
11.
Oh, jeez.
Let me see if I can...
What happens if I speed up just slightly?
Not bad.
I mean...
You know.
We're trying to offset that little bit.
Why can't I speed up?
There we go.
Okay, we're back at...
Oh, this is not good!
Oh, no!
Wait, are we gonna overheat?
We're like a cruise missile.
Oh, jeez.
Please don't overheat.
Altitude is...
Going up!
Nice!
So we cross periopsis.
Intersect looking good.
Five kilometers.
Look, we're catching up to Sherlock because we're in such a low orbit.
He's at 76 kilometers.
We also currently have a connection to whatever this is up here.
I wonder if there's actually, like, a model on the planet.
If you were to land there, maybe you can see, like, a satellite dish or something.
An antenna, whatever.
I can't go faster.
But, hey, at least we're not burning up as much anymore.
This is very little burning.
It's a light char, you know?
Intersect there.
11 kilometers now.
Okay, let's stop now.
No more burning.
We're done burning.
As soon as we get over there, we're gonna start to burn towards the target.
What is my altitude?
57.
Okay, okay.
Just get me out of the atmosphere, please.
I get nervous when I'm this low, you know?
Let me see the contract.
Save Sherlo Kerman.
Recover Sherlo Kerman on Kerman.
Good.
Good, good, good.
We can even do the trick where we take control of Sherlo and just have him fly to our ship again.
That worked beautifully last time.
62.
Wait, we're right next to each other right now.
Let me see if I can actually, uh...
Look at that!
He's right there!
You can even see the little spacecraft in the distance.
I don't know if you can, but I can.
There's a tiny dot moving.
Wait, I have an idea.
Do I see you?
Maybe the little, uh...
square is not showing up when you're looking through a window.
And again, he was in front of the sun there, so I think the angle is just not good for me here.
Yeah.
Angle is bad.
That's fine.
Let's see the intersect.
Nine kilometers.
I don't think it's gonna get better than that.
It's about nine kilometers.
We're also approaching the edge of space now, so that's not gonna change anymore.
Speed up even more.
God, this game is so satisfying.
Like, when you manage to do these little things here, like, creating this intersect, it feels incredible.
Look, it's like a racetrack!
Look, all three of us.
Isn't that cool?
I'm in the lead right now.
The crew, too.
Sherlo number two, and we got Valentina tailing behind.
Or trailing behind.
So, let me see here.
Approach info for Sherlo.
We have intersect one in two minutes and 26 seconds.
Let me put it on target now.
Wait, really?
Is the target that way?
There's no way.
No, the target's there.
Why are you pointing that way?
Oh, it's because you're pointing at prograde.
I see.
You're not actually pointing at the target.
Let's see if I can find the target.
That's away from the target, so it should be right opposite on this nav ball.
There we go.
Ten kilometers?
Speed up slightly.
Notice how he's moving this way, so I need to burn, like, sort of here.
So that would be, like...
I'm looking at my actual craft right now, not even the nav ball.
Like...
there-ish.
Maybe I should wait with burning.
We have intersect in...
No, no.
Let's burn now.
We should be moving towards the target now.
This is set towards the target.
I think.
Where's my...
Oh, there it is.
Okay, so we do this.
Yep.
Keep burning opposite here, so we bring the velocity vector on top of the target indicator.
We don't want to go too fast, though.
We're currently at 50 kilometers.
Or, sorry.
50 meters per second.
Let's turn around now and get ready to burn opposite.
Here.
I'm gonna burn slightly right...
We have so much fuel!
Look at that!
Dude, we can do this for days.
If only I had room for more, I could have gone for Valentina, too.
Okay, 42 meters per second.
I'm gonna speed up a little bit here.
Five kilometers.
We're getting closer.
Okay, now I'm gonna burn again.
Add a bit more.
Bring that right on top of it.
There we go.
Fast forward.
Oh, there it is.
Let's start to slow down.
Like, significantly slow down.
11.
Okay, we can wait a bit more.
Here he comes.
Dude, this is so sick.
Very slow burn now.
0.5 meters per second.
I'll take that.
And now we have to switch.
Which is...
That one.
Sherlo's craft.
Sherlo, my dude!
Are you ready?
Is that...
Wait, Vessel.
That's Valentina.
That's me.
We're so close.
There we go.
Did you get all your snacks?
Let's go.
I'm coming!
Look at it getting bigger.
Oh!
The darkness!
Slow down.
Slow down, Turbo.
Dude, this is like textbook at this point.
Also, wait!
Activate the lights.
Oh, man!
Let's get inside.
We did it!
He's in it!
Okay, let's now...
Get down again.
But we're gonna do it on the bright side of the planet.
Let's speed up a little bit.
Meanwhile, I'm leaving a bunch of debris behind.
Again.
Here we come.
Yo, look at this!
Is that the...
What?
Chicstulu crater, whatever it's called, equivalent on this planet?
Definitely a crater.
You know, the one that took out the dinosaurs on Earth.
Maybe we try and land in that.
Ah, it's gonna be too steep of an angle, I think.
Now, let's not fuck this up.
Last time I had this on target, and I wasted a bunch of fuel.
Orbit.
Retrograde.
Also, I feel like burping all the time for some reason.
This Foxy Crunty is getting the better of me.
Alright, Churlo!
Hold on to your hats and goggles!
It's gonna get real.
Feel those G-forces?
Get used to it.
Let's see.
Nah, way more.
Way more.
But it is kinda scary, cause we are still in the shaker configuration.
Okay, that should do it.
Okay.
Separation coming up!
In three...
two...
one...
Separation successful.
What's that up there?
Oh, that's his Churlo's craft.
Okay, cool.
He's still in orbit, of course.
Well, the craft is.
Okay.
Now we should be falling into the atmosphere, and everything should be Gucci.
Let's also get ready with, uh...
the right configuration here.
Surface.
We're going on the surface.
What's that?
Jewel.
Jewel rise.
Sweet.
Wait.
Okay.
The games are over.
It's time for actual re-entry.
Churlo Kerman has been saved.
Isn't it cool, all three of us?
It's like a fighter craft, you know, breaking off formation.
I'm going down, boys.
You continue without me.
Oh, here we go.
I still have it on 4X.
Because I'm a little...
impatient bitch.
And this is getting to be, you know, just another Tuesday.
In the Kerbal Space Program.
But that's okay.
Let's slow down a little bit now.
I...
Dude, I would say at this point, the Shaker has...
has freaking earned its place in this space program.
It is so proven at this point.
It's beautiful.
Just beautiful.
Drogues shoots are up.
We can also deploy the other ones, but let's wait a bit.
So we get down even faster.
Okay.
Normal shoots.
So the Drogues deploy at 2.5, and the normal ones at 1.
1,000.
There we go.
Oh.
Sorry!
Oh, God.
Imagine sitting in here.
I would be so sick.
Yikes.
Stabilize.
Dude, part of me wants to just play the entire game from inside the vehicle like this.
That would also be kind of cool, right?
There's something about looking through the window that you don't get from the external view.
The sense of scale, right?
Something about it.
Are we in the desert again?
Hold on.
Yep.
Those are cacti.
Here we go.
Ready for touchdown.
4.7-ish meters per second.
Very good.
Whoa.
And we made it to the surface, boys.
Kind of want to go for an EVA.
Sherlock, you deserve to go outside.
All hatches are obstructed.
Okay, never mind.
Whatever.
Okay.
Mission successful.
We even got some science out of it.
No, that was the last mission.
Never mind.
And look at our money just going up.
We're doing contracts, baby.
Total reputation, 17.
Means we're no longer in the negative.
That's good.
And look at this.
Zero active contracts.
Guys, it's time.
We are going to go to the moon.
And we're going to land on the moon.
In fact, I'm so sure of it.
No, wait, wait, wait.
What about Valentina?
I forgot about Valentina.
Fuck.
Maybe we don't need her for this.
Okay, check this out.
What if...
What if we go rescue Valentina...
And in the same mission...
Go straight to the moon?
Okay, maybe that's a little too crazy, actually.
It sounds fun, but...
Let's not go too wild.
That's maybe a little crazy.
We have enough data on the moon.
Oh, wait a minute.
There's also other moons.
Moons.
Right?
There's a moon here!
We could check that out, too.
It's at a bit of an inclination.
We could do either, actually.
And if we get here, and we just do like a...
Like an orbit or whatever, a flyby, and do science, we're going to get a lot of science, probably.
Right?
This may actually be a better idea.
Or we go even further.
Oh, my gosh.
Damn.
I'm so excited.
I really am.
Okay.
Let's start with the moon, shall we?
I mean...
It feels like the right progression, you know?
To go moon, and then to the next one.
But I guess they're both kind of part of the Kerbin system.
Also, what?
So...
Carson's debris.
What am I going to do with this?
How would I ever de-orbit this?
I guess I would somehow...
Get up there, bring a rocket up to it, and somehow attach it to the rocket, and then...
Do a de-orbit burn?
Or what?
What?
This is the one with Valentina.
What is that?
Terminate.
Oh, maybe I can just...
This will destroy the vessel, killing all crew in it.
Are you sure you want to continue?
But there's nobody in it.
Will it say the same thing on all?
Okay.
Ah, alright, there we go.
Clean up the freaking space debris.
Why can't I...
Oh, there we go.
Beautiful.
Can I rename this?
Somehow.
Maybe not.
Ah.
Okay.
Well, that's better.
It's going to be much easier now to see what's going on.
Guys, I think we got to go rescue Valentina first.
The crew has one more mission.
The crew too.
I mean.
And maybe we...
Oh, Sherlock was an engineer.
Interesting.
And he has one star.
So look at this now.
Provides repair skills.
Repack parachutes?
Engineer can repair failures.
Deploy power generation units.
What?
I'm so confused by all that.
But it's cool, I guess.
Wait, Carson is our only pilot.
We kind of need Valentina then.
Like, no question about it.
Let me quickly see where she is.
Because we should wait for her to come by again.
This is like, the way to do it.
We're doing rescue missions back to back here.
Okay, you're right there.
I guess I can wait for you to take a trip around.
It's like 20 minutes or so, right?
Actually, less maybe.
It's like 15 minutes-ish?
Wee!
Oh, don't go too fast.
I hope Valentina isn't starving.
Okay, so she's here now-ish.
Now.
Here I come!
Uh, here.
And then...
Let me just double-check.
Yes.
Carson.
That one, these two.
That one, this one.
Dude, we don't even need all this delta-V, actually.
We can even- we can calm down a bit.
We had way more than we needed last time.
Let's not go too crazy.
That's all we need.
Boom.
Hell yeah.
Let's go.
Cheers.
Carson!
Lift off again!
We are going to get Valentina.
Let's see where she is.
She's coming right there.
This is so fucking sick!
Dude, I love the rescue mission!
It's so dope.
Very nice.
Also, I forgot how much this rocket is worth.
Maybe it's like 10,000 or so?
Well, that's definitely, uh, less than what Valentina's worth, right?
In fact, I'm gonna slightly turn if I can.
Looks like I can.
Slightly.
Hey, I'm surprised I can turn this much already.
I wonder why that is.
Maybe it's because I'm moving a little slower.
So in time to separate.
Stages.
Carson is loving it.
Kind of wish you could give these guys haircuts.
I would love Carson to have, like, a mohawk.
Imagine.
Or put glasses on them or something.
Okay, now we start turning even more.
I'm getting better at this, dude.
Also, let me see the orbital parameters.
Looking good.
I need to see which height she's at.
Almost a hundred.
A hundred kilometers.
That's cool.
We can go a little more horizontal here.
In fact, we can go very horizontal.
I love the way you can see the gimbal of the engine, too, when I steer it.
It's a nice detail.
Here I come.
I should actually slow down.
Or not go as high yet.
I want to stay a little below her so I can potentially catch up to her.
She's ahead of me.
Oh, we're going a little too high.
I'm going to try and bring it down just slightly.
It looks weird, the angle, but...
I think it's fine.
I'm looking at this number here.
Apoapses.
Okay, we're going to run out of fuel here in a sec.
Oh, god.
Slow down even more.
Further down.
Just stay below her orbit.
That's all I want right now.
Okay, good.
Oh, we're a little far behind.
87 meters.
87,000 meters.
So, we're at...
Oh, we're at 1,900.
We don't need a lot here.
This is going to be quite fast.
So, let's burn in...
Oh, god.
Let me estimate.
This is going to take...
It's going to take 20...
30 seconds.
25 seconds.
That means we're going to start burning when this is like 12-ish seconds.
I'm going to fast forward slightly.
Get ready.
There we go.
Valentina!
By the way, I definitely took notice now that we need to have the vessel that we're trying to reach be a little further behind than what I had it here.
Looks good.
Target.
Oh, wait.
The inclination is a little off here.
Let me see exactly where it differs.
It's like right here, right?
It's like there.
Actually, it's right at periapsis.
So, if I want to change that, I want to burn up over here to bring that up there, which is going to bring this down.
What is up?
Wait, this is the way I'm facing now.
Nope.
Wrong one.
There we go.
Oh, I guess that's what that means then.
It's like normal.
To the velocity vector.
Right-hand rule.
Okay, so let's wait a bit.
This looks about right.
Pretty good.
But now we need to find out how to actually get to catch up to her.
We actually have kind of an encounter here.
Hmm.
We're a little too far out here.
Kind of want to burn retrograde right now.
Which means I'm going to bring apwapsis down slightly.
Which means we're going to catch up.
Burning very slowly here.
Beautiful.
The question is...
Ah, we're still below the atmosphere.
I burned a little too much, but, you know, it's better than 52.
Last time I was at 52.
Haha.
This is going to be much easier.
So, basically, you want to be in a lower orbit than the one you're trying to get up to.
Because then you move faster, right?
This is why we're catching up to him now.
Or her, I mean.
Okay, so I think we just entered atmosphere.
We're not going to speed up a lot.
I mean, slow down a lot.
It's going to be very slight.
Actually, you know what I think?
Instead of trying to get into an orbit that is lower than the target, maybe it just, in general, makes more sense to go into a higher orbit.
Because that way, you're not going to have the atmosphere problem, and you're just going to let them catch up to you, instead of me catching up to them like I'm doing now.
Yeah.
Actually, that makes so much sense.
Let's do that next time.
That makes a lot of sense.
It's now 32 kilometers.
I feel like we should do that.
Yeah.
It's changing a lot, because we're moving through the atmosphere.
We're slowing down.
But it doesn't look like we're slowing down, but we kind of are.
We're bleeding off energy.
The reason why we're bleeding off, or it looks like we're still speeding up, is because we're moving towards periapsis.
Okay.
Plenty of fuel, man.
This is an easy one.
We got this one in the bag, homie.
Valentina can finally come home and eat lunch.
She must be starving.
I wonder how long she's been up here.
Can I, like, see a mission time on this vessel?
Maybe I can do it from the tracking center.
In fact, hold on.
I can do that right now.
Switch two.
Cannot switch vessels while in atmosphere.
Okay.
I see.
I guess because it's like a perilous situation.
When you're in space, things are more or less guaranteed to stay as they are, you know, assuming you're in a stable orbit and all that.
But I wonder, if I move to ap-wapsis here, and then I try to switch vessel, if it's going to let me then, or it's going to say, your current orbit will intersect atmosphere, so you can't switch, you know?
Maybe.
Also, what is this little...
Oh!
It's like a little shortcut.
You can make a alarm for periapsis.
That's neat.
Very good.
Oh, I didn't mean to do that.
No, cancel.
There you go.
Man, this is also the problem, by the way, by going through the atmosphere, is that you can't speed up very much, so you're just forced to watch this unfold in slow motion.
Catching up.
What's our approach looking like?
Not great.
This is what's happening when you go through the atmosphere.
Another reason not to go low, right?
We have like three major reasons now.
I feel like I should slow down even more.
Let's see.
That's bad.
And it's not because we're going to be too fast.
It's because the actual separation here is different now.
If I burn here, that is...
Yeah, so let's just increase that slightly.
And it makes sense.
Listen, we lost speed going through the atmosphere.
What we want to do is burn Probe right now to gain that speed back.
If you think about it, it makes a lot of sense.
Stop!
What?
I misclicked!
Okay, it's actually okay, I guess.
Somehow.
I fucking clicked the wrong button, and then it went super...
Sado mode.
I forget the name of that.
39 kilometers.
What's it look like if I give it a bit more?
We actually have a pretty good insect over here.
Look at that.
20.
Yeah.
I fucked it up just now.
I did.
Maybe I'll go for this one instead.
Just tell me we're not gonna...
Oh.
Okay, okay, good.
We're not gonna go through the atmosphere until then.
1.6.
I like it.
Speed it up.
Beautiful.
It is a little tedious, though, doing this.
But not in a bad way, you know?
You just gotta...
Do it in a...
I guess there's...
So, if I had...
You know, waited until the target was a little further behind...
It's like a trial and error thing.
Then I wouldn't have to go through all this waiting.
Preparation matters.
We could also go for this one here.
Honestly, I'm feeling it.
We don't have to wait for the purple.
Speeding.
The final frontier.
What's lurking out there?
Oh my god.
40 kilometers?
Dude, we should wait for this one.
Yeah.
Fuck the...
Fuck the orange one.
We're going purple.
Yeah.
Here I come.
I'm coming for you, Valentina.
10 kilometers?
Not bad.
I'm gonna put you in my death pod.
Target.
94 meters per second.
Where are you?
There you are.
Am I moving towards you or away from you?
I'm moving towards you.
Okay.
Interesting.
So, basically...
Let me think.
We gotta do something like this.
It's like...
It's like herding sheep.
The retro is the sheep.
I'm the dog.
Or...
The Marston.
I be the Marston.
Closer and closer.
Soon, Valentina will be in my hands.
And I will feed her.
She hasn't eaten in a lot of days.
Looks good.
Now we wait.
You can even see the way they're moving, right?
Nice.
Seven meters.
Still drifting a little off mark there.
There we go.
Four meters.
Here we go.
I'm making it very easy for Valentina here.
One meters per second.
Zero point nine.
Zero point one.
Boom.
Valentina, it's time to leave.
This vessel is no good anymore.
In fact, didn't she have science?
She has science on her.
Let me look at your situation.
Okay, you've got fuel.
You've got fuel.
Actually, this is making me want to watch.
You've got mail.
Is that what it's called, that movie?
Is it you've got mail?
There's a movie like that.
Like a love movie.
Romance.
Oh god, this game is so fucking cool!
I mean, look at this!
And there's the earth!
Ha ha!
Valentina, we did it!
Get in!
You glorious son of a bitch!
It's celebration time!
Oh wait, I can't get in.
Oh wait, it's because...
I had the UI off.
I was waiting for the prompt.
There we go!
We're in!
Now!
Now it's time to...
What's this?
Oh, we have a closed intersect here, but we are already intersecting.
So, what do you mean?
Stop.
Can I untarget somehow?
Wait, is there like a keybind to untarget?
I need to see my cheat sheet.
Oh god, I don't have it open.
Cheat sheet.
There you go.
Bring it over here on this window.
Let's see.
EVA.
No.
Untarget.
I don't see it.
But that's okay.
Okay, let's just do a retro burn here.
It's time to go home.
Alright, Valentina.
I brought the fuel.
Notice this one now.
It's gonna go above us soon.
See?
We're slowing down.
We're going on an arc down now.
You know what I love about this game?
It's like, it's really realistic with the physical rules here and laws.
You know, you're like, I can predict what's gonna happen before it happens.
Just by intuition.
And that's cool.
That it's that precise, you know?
Like, it may not be 100% precise, but it's like, good enough.
You know what I mean?
Ooh, that's a very steep angle I got there.
Maybe I should burn a little...
I do trust the shaker, but I'm not sure if I trust it that much.
You know what I mean?
What is this A-N?
Oh, ascending node.
Why is it wobbling?
Why are you always wobbling?
Mm-mm, my god.
Stop fucking wobbling!
And we're off.
Turn around.
Man, that is just turning on a dime.
Incredible performance of this little spacecraft here.
Those reaction wheels must be crazy.
Valentina?
You're coming home.
And then when you're home, I got a surprise for you.
Yes, it's lunch, but there's more.
We are gonna go to the moon.
And I kinda wanna bring more than one Kerbal.
You know?
It can't just be one.
That would be...
kinda messed up, honestly.
Okay, here we go.
The shaker is gonna prove itself once again.
Let me also put this in...
surface mode.
Oh, that's a fantastic angle.
Look at that.
I guess Valentina would be...
right above me that way.
Oh, god.
Wait,
the flag is burning!
Look at that!
The flag on one of the capsules is burning because it's like angled in the plasma.
I wonder if the flag can burn off or get charred or something.
That would be kinda cool.
Yo, you know what we have to try at some point?
We have to try re-entry with a bare Kerbal.
No clothes.
Naked.
Through the atmosphere.
See how they burn up to a crisp.
I just wanna see, you know?
What is gonna happen?
I'm curious.
And if you think about it, you can definitely de-orbit a Kerbal.
You just use your...
uh...
jetpack thrusters to burn retro.
Ha ha ha!
Like...
What is gonna...
Are they just gonna...
Are they actually gonna...
Is there gonna be an animation of them burning up?
Like, I'm so curious.
But obviously, we're only gonna do it to the Kerbals that have committed a vast crime.
You know?
Maybe...
A Kerbal that completely ruined a mission on purpose or something.
A saboteur, you know?
Somebody who deserves it.
Okay.
Looking good so far.
Shoots!
Deployed.
I always get such a shock from that.
There go the main shoes.
Oi, oi, oi.
I guess the main shoes really bring this out of, uh...
What do you call it?
Balance.
Man, what of you.
Cheers, guys.
Happy Wednesday.
I'm having such a blast with this game, man.
What a...
What a beautiful piece of art, you know?
If people say video games are stupid, they have no idea what they're saying.
Like, they don't know about this game.
Not only that, it's also educational.
Like, does it get any better, you know?
It's like the perfect video game.
Once again in the desert.
There's lots of desert here on this planet.
We...
We have landed.
This thing is just rolling.
Nice.
Valentina is home safe.
Cheers.
And it's the middle of the night.
Carson, Valentina.
How come they're not gaining any experience?
Maybe experience can only be earned when you do a contract.
Or maybe it's something where you have to do something you haven't done before.
Such as, for example, going to Minmus, right?
That is something I haven't done.
So maybe that will give them some more experience.
Okay, let's just warp to sunrise.
It's dark and gloomy right now.
We don't like dark and gloomy.
Nice.
Okay.
Um...
Now...
It's time for the moon!
I was gonna say we bring more Kerbals, but do we really want to bring a Shaker to the moon?
I...
Don't think so, man!
I really don't think so.
Let's make a new craft.
Actually, no.
Uh...
Let's make...
Let's use something we already have as a basis.
The moon explorer, maybe.
No.
I need something with the science module on that I had.
Because we're definitely doing science there.
Maybe we even, uh...
What do you call it?
Transmit the science.
Was it Jebediah?
This one is 14,000.
What the hell is that?
Hey!
This looks like it!
I like this design already.
Very nice.
Yeah!
Great!
And then we have the science, uh...
Junior.
Which we're gonna discard.
Because we're gonna grab the science and put it in the little science box.
Now, if we're gonna go to the moon and land...
Uh...
I guess we would need landing legs.
Yeah.
Let me read about this.
Stress tolerance is like...
What is that?
Uh...
10 million?
I can't fucking read all these heroes.
Retractable.
Suspension travel 0.8 meters.
Okay.
Uh...
Wait, let me think.
So basically, this is the idea.
Oh wait, we also gotta go back.
Oh sh...
Oh shit.
Guys.
This is actually a crazy risky mission.
A lot has to go right here.
This is kinda nuts, actually.
Maybe I don't bring the science junior.
Maybe I...
It's too greedy.
You know?
This is...
This is pure greed.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I can't do it.
Uh...
Shit.
Wait, I'm trying to think.
So we launch booster out of the atmosphere.
We go into orbit with the second stage.
Right?
And...
Then we have the third stage here.
This third stage needs to do a lot of work.
We would have to be landing this whole thing then.
Dude, what?
Can I make this like...
Less...
Tall?
No, shit.
Okay.
Oh god.
I mean, I guess...
I will say though, this doesn't look very stable.
You know what I mean?
It looks like it's like the tiniest breeze is gonna flip this over.
Then again, there's no breeze on the moon.
But there is bad piloting.
I want this to be less tall.
Maybe we expand...
What do you call it?
Tanks?
Not in vertical, but in horizontal.
Like that one.
This looks like what I need, actually.
Give me that.
Holy fucking shit.
Never mind.
I thought it was like a tiny one.
Brother.
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I know what to do.
Watch this.
We're gonna do...
Wait.
Get rid of this.
I wanna use this stuff.
Because see, we get thicker now.
We could even do...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
We do this.
That.
And...
It's so big.
Wait, can I not just...
Inverse shaker?
Oh my god, it's beautiful.
It's like a little thick boy.
I like it.
But wait a minute.
This is...
Ah!
Hey, hey, guys.
Wait, that works?
No way.
They're gonna be blasted off.
Eh, it's not gonna work.
Never mind, never mind.
But we could also inverse this part.
We're almost at 10,000 already, man.
These parts are costing a lot.
I don't think I like that.
What about this guy?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Looking kind of like the spaceship now with all the...
Or the starship.
With all the little engines down there, doesn't it?
It's kind of cool.
I do kind of want to try this.
But isn't that also too tall, though?
Legs.
Oh, my God, bro.
I think this is not gonna work.
Never mind.
Scrap that.
Scrap the idea.
Ah!
Or...
Or we do this.
Wait.
Hold on.
Oh, actually, yes.
Eh?
Maybe?
And then...
How does that help me, though?
Ah, shit.
The angle is bad.
Oh, my God.
I guess I could do this, actually.
I could just put it like that.
Simplicity, man.
Ah!
Hey!
Look at that one!
I like!
So, wait.
This one has how much?
Uh...
Wait.
What does it say?
Oh, oh.
72.
And then we have two of these.
So, that's like 272.
Compared to...
Ah, it's like...
It's almost the same, right?
But that's okay.
I mean, the idea is just to have this be a little wider.
So it's more stable on the ground.
We can add one more, even.
I actually like that.
Yeah.
I like that.
However, this engine is not very strong.
It's gonna have to do a lot of work to, you know, push this bastard up.
But wait.
Let's not forget.
We need to connect this with the rest.
So how we do that?
Wait, is that...
Is that good, though?
I mean, I guess it doesn't matter for going up.
Yeah, actually, it's fine.
It's just a little scuffed, isn't it?
It doesn't look that good.
Do I just...
Is it just that simple?
Wait.
Get rid of this.
Also, this is going to be...
Uh...
Moon...
Lander.
We're going there.
To touch it.
Save that.
Okay, I actually kind of like the look of this.
It's not that bad.
I can even make it black.
Just to differentiate it a little bit.
Can I change this one, too?
Yeah.
Oh, that was inside, I guess.
That's cool.
Alright.
Nice.
What next?
So, let me see here.
3,120...
Delta V.
We can definitely do better than that.
Let's see what the status is.
So, we currently have...
Okay.
Dude.
We have a massive booster, don't we?
Guys, I think it's time.
It's time to do something drastic.
Fuck this shit.
We're going to go crazy with it.
Watch this.
Ooh, it's 12,000 already.
Damn.
Okay.
Let's do...
Was that the...
Oy.
650...
No.
570 at...
Surface level.
Or sea level.
That is insane.
And...
Let me think.
Yes.
Ah, but wait, wait.
Oh!
I was about to say, we can't put it down here.
Because we don't have a decoupler big enough.
But, we do have this.
So, watch this.
I'm just gonna...
Make this orange.
Can I...
Oh, that's beautiful!
Maybe we can make it better.
No, this is definitely the best.
Oh my god.
Yes!
Um...
We're gonna put...
Four!
Four.
Look how tiny it is!
We're going like, uh...
Wide on this one.
Actually, this is the wide boy.
Uh, the...
The mooner...
Wide...
Boy.
That's what that is.
And then we have engines.
222,000 for a single rocket so far.
And we're gonna go even crazier.
Wait, this only adds 500 extra DEV?
No, wait.
Oh.
I guess I...
I placed it wrong.
Guys, this one, I think, has enough juice...
To get us there.
But, holy shit, it's expensive.
These boosters are worth a fortune.
We can't do that.
What about these guys?
This is ridiculous.
This is too much.
Can you please...
Get on there?
There we go.
Hey, I actually...
Kinda like that?
Maybe?
Let me...
Let me actually test something.
So, what if I only do three?
Like that.
Okay.
4,550.
What if I only do two?
Oh, wait.
Can I just...
Oh.
This is much better.
Okay.
So, we save only 200...
Let me try this now.
I mean, it is going up.
But this is getting ridiculous.
This is ridiculous.
It's too much.
Stop.
Let's do two.
Okay.
So, 4,400.
Let's try to replace this with that.
Ooh.
5,000, baby.
And it's only 26k.
I mean, only and only.
But, you know.
We're doing it.
I feel like...
Okay, hold on.
Aerodynamically, this could pose a problem, though.
This is kinda...
Weird shape, isn't it?
It's a weird shape.
Also, I need to...
Start retracted.
Wait, deploy shielded?
Huh?
It don't do nothing.
Ah, keep him black.
I like that.
We need to put some aerodynamicity on this.
There, this is my Magnus open.
Opus.
Uh, wait.
Move.
Wait, wait.
I need to see the, uh...
Center of mass.
Okay, well.
We're good on that.
Okay.
Now, I think we need to apply some sort of...
Just to make it look cool.
Some winglets.
Let's make four of these.
I said four.
Hello?
There we go.
Ooh, sexy.
Me likey.
That's not...
Oh my god.
Ooh, dude.
Okay, so wait.
Let's actually run through.
Let's see now.
We're gonna do booster and this engine at the same time.
Just like real life.
Ah, wait a sec.
There's something I don't like here.
When we detach these, they make...
You see how the center of mass of these boosters...
They're gonna go in like that, aren't they?
We need to bring this point higher up.
Oh god.
Uh...
Shit.
Move this guy.
Oh god, really?
I can't...
Let's put them like here.
So wait, I'll be turn...
If I turn this way...
Then I should probably have them like this.
Just so they go out...
Out of my way, right?
I don't want to turn into them.
Actually, I'm...
I'm glad I just...
Saw that.
I think it's...
Better.
A little further down.
Why are they like going into it like that?
Something's wrong.
There we go.
They're still a little too high.
That's it, baby.
That's it.
These two.
Uh, this engine goes with it.
These two go away.
And then this.
But maybe we want to...
Be a little more granular here.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, dude, okay, dude, okay, dude, okay, dude.
Guys?
Watch this.
We're not done.
We bring the science back.
I'm a greedy boy.
I believe, I believe, I believe.
Look how big it is now.
I mean, surely it'll be stable, right?
Wait, did that just remove 300?
Delta V?
Really?
Wait, how did I have 5,000 before?
What did I change?
Wait, what?
Oh, also, let's have more of these.
Let's have one down here, or like here as well.
I wish it wouldn't do that.
Okay.
I like it.
I actually don't know how we just, uh, lost that Delta V, but okay.
Whatever.
Science is coming.
We're going all in with this.
Okay, so these two at first, and then...
These four.
Right?
And then this one, that one...
Bomb, bomb, bomb.
Dude, we got it.
Who's going?
Ooh, it's gotta be...
It's gotta be Valentina.
She deserves the glory and the honor of going to the moon.
Since she spent all that time in orbit, left behind.
Right?
How much money is this now?
Ooh, 32,000.
Yikes.
This better work!
Uh...
I've never had this much Delta V.
This is gonna be crazy.
Okay, here we go.
You ready?
Boom.
Oh!
No!
We need...
Less than 30 parts.
Oh my god, really?
Wait.
Uh, save.
We need to upgrade this building.
No!
My magnum opus!
Okay, fuck these things, I guess.
What else can I save away?
Um...
We don't need the parachutes, too.
Just kidding.
Do we really need these?
I don't know.
Uh...
Where are we?
Third!
We have four parts gone?
Bro...
No...
No way...
What?
Uh...
Is it all...
Maybe...
Okay, wait.
Oh, shit.
No.
Wait, how do I...
How is this many parts?
This doesn't even make sense.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8...
Oh, I guess the legs count as 4.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I know what we're gonna do.
We're gonna repli... These are three parts.
We don't need to...
Oh, here it is, here it is.
I see what's going on.
Easy fix, actually.
Get rid of this.
Uh...
Is it that one?
Oh, nice.
Nice.
Uh, we can probably reduce it even more.
Nine tons?
This is like two of these, then.
Oh my god, yes.
Yes.
Oh, I have to redo it.
No.
Wait, hold on.
Uh, put this here.
Get rid of these.
Um...
Man, what a mess.
Maybe that's too much?
I don't know.
Oh, that looks very nice, actually.
Oh, yeah.
Hell yeah.
Very nice.
So now we are at 21.
Nice.
Now we need the, uh...
Legs.
One, two, three.
Okay, wait.
We need to...
I can actually do this even better.
Watch.
Can I not, uh...
Yeah, I was about to say.
Yeah, change the orientation there.
Why is it not smooth?
Why?
Oh, wait.
Is it because of this?
Ah.
There we go.
We get a little bit more, uh...
Girth.
Which is what we want.
Fantastic.
Save it.
And then...
Um...
Retract this.
I like that sound, punk.
And now we should be good to go.
So wait, how many parts?
25.
We can have...
Two of these.
That's 27.
And then we can only have two decoubblers then.
Shit.
Okay, that's probably fine then.
Whatever.
Let's have it be right there.
There.
Beautiful.
Look at that.
And then we...
Oh, wait.
30...
Wait, how?
Oh, did I...
Wait, something's off here.
There's two of them.
Ah.
It was bugging.
Oh, hell yeah.
We even have more delta V now somehow.
I don't understand, but...
Maybe I'm not supposed to.
So we are at 29.
Oh, I wish I could put both of these on, but I can't.
Do we get rid of one more thing?
Do we really need two drogue parachutes?
Methinks we don't.
I'm gonna go ahead and...
Oh my god.
Maybe we do one of these.
Ha ha ha.
I mean...
Is that a good idea?
That's a terrible idea.
That's terrible.
I feel like we need the...
Two drogues there.
It makes sense.
What can I save away here?
Maybe I just go like this.
Fuck it, right?
Or I remove a thermometer.
Nah, we wanna measure the moon.
Right?
Guys, the moon or white boy?
Is off.
These three.
Those two.
That one.
Oh!
I gotta go take a piss.
And then I'm ready.
Be right back.
All right.
Oh, yeah.
Let's go.
Valentina, you glorious bastard.
I hope you won't perish.
The thing I'm most worried about is actually these boosters.
I'm worried about them not being aerodynamic.
That's like the thing, you know?
Okay.
Here we go.
Are we ready?
Go.
Oh, that's a lot of speed.
Maybe I actually slow down a bit.
It's looking pretty stable.
It's looking pretty good.
I like it.
It is beautiful.
In fact, I want to get rid of these solid boosters ASAP.
I'm so scared of when I detach them.
I'm gonna slow down just a bit.
I'm gonna start turning slightly as well.
Okay.
Oh, no.
We're rotating for some reason.
I'm gonna try and counteract that.
Counteract the rotation.
Good.
Valentina is experienced.
She knows what's up.
And she knows which way is down.
Oh!
See ya!
Oh my god, that's crazy.
Bye-bye.
That's fucking awesome.
Yeah.
Oh, we gotta go faster.
Faster, faster, faster, faster, faster, faster, faster, faster.
Max speed, max speed, max speed.
Uh, put the maneuver mode on.
Appwaps at 51 already.
Sweet.
Jesus.
Those were some powerful boosters.
We can start turning slightly then.
Let me see the map.
Okay.
It doesn't...
Like, I was expecting this engine to be really crazy.
It doesn't feel that crazy, does it?
Ah, maybe it is kinda crazy.
But it's not, like, super crazy.
Let's just give it a lot of horizontal, uh, component on the velocity here.
In fact, I'm gonna go even a little down like that.
Just to keep the appwapses around 100...
kilometers.
Dude, we can even...
Maybe get to orbit on...
On this stage?
Ooh!
It's gonna go fast.
This engine is powerful.
I take it back.
Let's guesstimate...
30 seconds.
Or maybe even, like, 25 seconds, so...
Wait, didn't I also do that last time?
But then I was at 1900, and I had the other engine, which was kinda bad.
I don't fuckin' know.
Let's just...
Eyeball it.
So we're gonna go to...
Here.
Burn!
It's not that fast, actually.
I expected this to be...
Going up...
Really fast.
But it's not doing that.
But the fact that we're almost in orbit, just with this stage, is insane.
2,300?
That's a beaut, Clark!
That's very nice.
Okay, so the moon is here.
We haven't even activated the last stage yet!
This is so good!
I feel great about this.
Okay, so we're gonna burn...
Let's see, it's there right now.
Last time I did...
It was like...
There, I think.
Oh man, we're almost there.
I feel like...
I could be lazy and burn now.
That's too much.
We gotta wait, we gotta wait.
It's...
No.
I'm gonna move around.
Oh man, the mission is on the way!
I'm coming for you, moon.
Just gotta have the right...
Configuration here.
So wait, right now we are angled...
Actually, we're perfect now.
Maybe a little more.
There.
That's perfect.
Now, we aim prograde.
Oh, look how...
Look how thick and big it is!
It has trouble...
Oh, there's a lot of mass to move here.
The reaction wheels...
Are having issues.
Okay, let's go.
Oh man, this engine is adding a lot real fast.
We're gonna run out of fuel, though, but that's okay.
We have the other engine ready.
Hot damn!
Oh my god.
Hoi!
Not bad!
Okay, Valentina!
Hit the switch!
In three...
Two...
One...
What happened?
What'd I do?
Oh no!
Did I click something?
Oh.
I was gonna...
I think I hit F3.
I was gonna hit F2 to remove the UI.
Oh, thank god the game didn't crash.
Oh my god.
I guess F3 just pauses.
Well, there you go.
We're back in it.
Oof.
That was a scary moment.
Ohoy!
Okay, okay.
Everything's fine.
God, it's so gorgeous.
Look at that.
Oh, and the moon is right there, too.
Oh, but wait.
We need to burn.
Hold on.
We're not done.
I was so enamored with this, I totally forgot we're not done burning.
Activate next stage.
Bye-bye.
Wait, what?
The moon encounter!
Is that the shit I unlocked?
Wait, hold on.
What am I seeing here?
Oh.
Oh, shit!
Patched conics!
We're moving from one conic here into another one, but this is going to be an escape trajectory, and we're going to be quite far away from the moon.
I guess I want this to be super close.
Maybe like that?
Why did the thing...
go away?
Wait, what?
Wait, are we crashing into the moon?
Dude, this is so sick!
Look at that!
Wait, at year one?
Day 21.
Okay.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Oh, that's cool!
Look, when I mouse over here, I can see where the moon is.
Ah!
That's...
Oh, that's really nice.
Is that his target?
Oh, right, just like, uh...
Rescue missions, you can see the closest approach, I guess.
Target position...
Wait, what?
But we should be fine.
We are on an...
on a course right now that takes us...
into the sphere of influence of the moon.
That's all I need.
Beautiful.
We are moon-bound!
You know what that means.
We gotta go for the view.
If we can get the moon in view here.
Where are you, moon?
Eh.
You're not wanting to do that, huh?
Okay.
Oh, it's because I have the...
SAS turned off.
It keeps rotating.
It's fine.
Let's just...
Let's just go.
Oh, that's fast.
Oy, oy, oy.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
This is looking bad.
No, it's good.
It does look kind of funky, though.
Oh, man.
What is that over there?
Oh, it's, uh...
It's Valentina's vessel.
The one she left behind when I rescued her.
Here we go.
Let's just see this.
Oh, we can easily see the moon now as well.
Last time, it was hidden by the sun.
And it was not visible.
Now we can really see it.
It's pretty.
Wait, rotating...
Wait, what?
Why can't I do this anymore?
Am I in the wrong mode again?
Why can't I do the thing?
What am I...
missing here?
Oh!
I was in time speed.
That's why.
There we go.
In fact, I know where the window is, so I can sort of angle it here.
Watch.
I'm gonna turn it like this, and it'll be in direct view now.
Fuck.
Almost.
Maybe.
I need to find it.
It's very important.
Oh, I guess it would be along the plane of the solar system and galaxy.
So let's just follow that.
We'll find it.
Oh!
I love when that happens.
You just see that come into view.
God damn, dude!
Like, oh, this is just my jam!
I love it!
Wow!
And the moon.
There it is.
I can't get enough!
Let's go!
We're speeding up.
Oh, God.
The time skip is so scary.
Oh, I can only go 50 now.
Is that because I'm close?
Oh, shit!
We are in the sphere of influence!
Oh, we're gonna be...
That is really close to the moon!
In fact, that looks like a collision course!
But hey, wait a minute.
Isn't that what we want?
We do intend to collide with the moon.
Just not violently.
In a very controlled manner.
Maybe it's okay.
In fact, let's use this.
Looks like we're gonna impact right here.
In fact, it looks like we're gonna impact a crater.
Sweet!
I say we go for it.
Ha ha ha ha!
So basically, what we have to do...
We just gotta burn retrograde all the time.
And if you think about it, the more retrograde we burn, the more steep the angle is gonna be until it's...
If we reach zero, you know, relative to the moon, we're gonna go straight down.
So let's just wait.
Oi, here we go!
Ho ho ho!
That's so fast!
I'm coming for you, moon!
Look at that scar across the face there.
Almost like a canyon.
That's interesting.
Earlier geologic activity.
Damn.
Oh god, that's...
Fucking slow down, slow down!
Damn!
We're also speeding up, of course.
I think it's time we may...
Let's start, uh...
Turning retro here.
Oh my god.
Wait a sec.
I forgot to take contracts!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
You're kidding me!
It's fine.
You know, I do it for the love of the game.
I don't care about no stinking contracts.
We're here for the actual mission itself.
Which is to land on the moon.
That's all that matters.
Fuck it.
I mean, not that we can do anything about it at this point.
We're committed.
We're going in.
Wow.
Oh, shit.
Man.
Oh, I can't believe it.
We could have had two co- Wait, wait, actually.
Wait a sec.
We are...
Can we not just go back?
It's ca- I can just go back via tracking?
Oh my god, never mind!
Ha ha!
Fuck that!
Yeah, here we go.
Okay, I don't do it for the love of the game.
I do it for the contracts, after all.
Uh, we have enough data on the moon to attempt the landing.
Oh, we could stage one.
Okay, we're definitely landing.
Boom.
And...
Maybe we do this one.
Bring Moonstone back with you.
Uh...
What else can I do on the moon?
Conduct temperature surveys.
Observational surveys?
Atmospheric surveys.
I guess it would have to be this one.
I don't see any other.
Related to the moon here.
We take that.
Good.
Tracking station.
Mooner white boy.
Oh yeah, we are...
Oh, wait.
Does the color indicate strength?
Of signal?
Maybe the signal right now is super weak.
You see that?
Usually it's green.
Interesting.
So I guess that's why you want a better antenna or whatever.
Okay, we're here now.
Now we have the contract.
Good, good, good.
Oh, man.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay, here we go.
The question is, when do I start burning?
I kind of want to start burning quite late.
Because if I start to burn now, we're going to start to land here.
Which is going to be in the dark.
And I don't like that.
The sun is there.
You know what we could do?
We could burn a little prograde first.
Just to...
Just to make sure that we land on the bright side.
Let's do that, actually.
Just give it a bit extra, you know?
I like it.
At least we're going to be on the...
Oh, wait.
Which way is the moon rotating?
It should rotate this way, right?
So maybe it's better if we land here.
I don't know how fast the moon rotates.
Is it going to rotate out of sun?
Ah, no way, right?
It should be fine.
Okay, now retrograde.
And now we wait.
Valentina.
We have lots of fuel.
But we also have...
Well...
Lots of fuel.
Which means...
It's going to be hella slow to burn this.
In fact, how slow is this?
I guess we'll find out.
Also, I guess at this point, I can just do this.
There's no atmosphere.
That was loud.
And there's no sound in space.
What's up with that, game?
Come on.
But maybe it's the sound she heard from inside.
You know, the gears are turning and all that.
Okay.
I guess I want to put it on surface.
We need to see our speed relative to the surface here.
Oh, wait a sec.
We also kind of need to figure out a...
Area to land that isn't, like...
Uh, hilly.
Oh, shit.
I guess we'll find out when we get closer.
Oh, why does the camera do that?
Let me start burning slightly.
Yeah, it's going down slow.
We can wait a bit more, I think.
Oh, god.
Actually, no.
I don't trust.
We're just gonna burn.
This is a lot of speed to get rid of here.
And not only that, we're going to speed up as we fall down, of course.
It looks kind of more nice over there compared to here.
But that could just be...
Some kind of, you know, visual...
Uh...
Thing that messes with my head.
Because there's more...
What do you call it?
Oh, god.
You know, light and dark.
There's a word for that.
In art.
Let me see the angle.
We should be going...
Yeah, look at this steep angle now.
We can wait a bit longer, I think.
God, imagine being inside of here, seeing that out your window.
I would be freaking terrified, man.
Holy shit.
55 kilometers.
We have plenty of time to burn.
And we have plenty of fuel, too.
And let's not forget, the more fuel we burn...
The more, um...
What do you call it?
The more effect the engine is going to have.
Because we're going to weigh less, right?
The mass is going to be lower.
I'm being reminded of one of my favorite movies now.
Called Gattaca.
Where there's such a kick-ass quote.
If you don't want to hear it...
You should mute for the next 20 seconds.
Because it'll be a spoiler.
But there's such a good quote in that movie.
Which is, I never saved anything for the return.
Or for the swim back, you know?
I hope I'm not going to be in that situation now.
I hope I have enough to get back.
But let's focus on landing first.
What's that?
Oh, look at his signal strength!
Curb and harvester massif.
Okay, well, there you go.
I mean, if I don't do anything now...
Valentina will die.
She's on a direct collision course.
I'm going to burn a bit more.
Actually, no.
I don't want to land in those craters.
Maybe we wait a bit more?
Oh, God.
We can burn...
Actually...
You know what?
Mathematically...
It makes more sense to burn close to the ground.
You want to burn...
When you're moving fast.
You know?
Because...
It's going as the square.
So when you add velocity...
Or subtract velocity...
It's going to have more impact...
When you're going faster.
That's why you want to burn at periapsis.
To increase apoapsis.
Because you're going the fastest.
Okay, let's burn like crazy now.
20,000 meters.
We have crossed the craters.
Maybe I pause a bit more.
Now.
220.
Wait, why is this pointing...
Shouldn't it point...
Oh, I guess we're still on a very parabolic arc.
If I burn to zero...
We're going to fall straight down.
Let's do a bit more.
I kind of like this.
This looks kind of flat, doesn't it?
Holy shit.
Ho, ho, ho.
Valentina.
I need you to log in.
This is it.
This is what we've been training for.
Still have a lot of fuel.
Come on.
Actually, I'm going to wait.
We're going to be super efficient here.
Ideally, the way you want to do this...
Is to do one continuous burn...
Until you stop burning right before the surface.
But obviously that requires calculation.
And we don't do that here.
Not at Kerbal Space Program.
We wing it.
Oh my god, look at all the detail popping in here.
Uh-oh.
Is that actually going to be a problem?
It doesn't feel like we're four kilometers away from the surface.
It feels like we're...
Way less.
Come on.
Yeah, now we're almost vertical.
See?
Valentina's excited.
Understandably.
We're going straight down now.
The shadow.
That's going to be the best indicator.
When they meet, then we're at the surface.
We're going to kick up some dust?
Oh shit.
What the fuck?
Oh!
Don't!
I didn't even realize the surface was so fucking tilted!
Holy shit!
Oh my god, we made it.
Get all the signs immediately.
Dude, my hands are shaking.
Oh!
Dude, my left hand is legit, like, shaking right now.
Oh my god.
The goo appears to be in the same state of awe as you are.
24 science!
Oh my god.
Pressure data.
28!
They say insanity is doing the same thing multiple times and expecting a different result.
You check the atmospheric pressure again anyways.
Damn right I do.
Temperature.
Dude, we're getting a shitload of science.
The thermometer can't seem to make up its mind whether it's hot or cold here.
This guy.
Material study.
60 science!
As you look away, one sample makes a run for it.
I don't give a shit about that sample.
Why are we not even maximizing here?
Oh wow.
Transfer data, man.
Done.
Okay, uh, crew report.
You feel awestruck at the beaten up nature of the moon.
I am awestruck, man.
I am.
Do we go for an EVA?
I've...
Okay, let's do it.
Is the weight gonna tip?
Okay, here we go.
Oh god.
Can you die from impact?
That's gotta be like an impact thing.
Oh my god.
Yep.
Reporting from the moon.
Oh my god, look at this little preview down there.
EVA report for sure.
Plant flag?
That's one small step for...
The situation is nominal?
That's beautiful.
Oh.
Uh.
I don't know.
Um.
Wide.
Site.
Or maybe we just name it...
The first landfall.
We come in peace.
Peace.
And we will...
Come again.
This is the start...
Of a beautiful...
Space program.
Oh my god.
Deploy shoot?
What's that gonna look like?
Let's not remove the helmet, shall we?
Can I...
Please tell me I can go first person on this.
Oh my god.
I wish I could see through the helmet.
I wanna look at...
I wanna look at things.
Wow.
No, don't overwrite.
Wait.
Uh, lower visor.
Yeah.
Now we look like an astronaut.
Look at that with the planet in the background too.
So cool.
Yeah, do some exercises.
Ooh!
Whoop!
Ha ha ha ha.
Wait, let me try this.
Uh.
Oh, that's not very...
Oh, never mind.
How much fuel do I have?
Four...
Okay, we have enough.
Wow.
God, it looks like such a...
An alien place, doesn't it?
Jewel.
The sun.
I almost wanna wait here for Earthrise.
It should appear over there, I guess.
Since this is like the, uh...
What do you call it?
The plane of the solar system, right?
50x.
We're just standing here.
Auto-saving.
I'm at...
Whoa!
Jesus!
What the...
It almost fell over!
Okay, we're not doing that again.
Holy crap!
I'm going back in.
Oh god, crap.
Get it!
Are we...
Are we tipping?
Wait, close this.
Dude, I have the finger on the trigger.
To blast off.
I'm ready to leave.
Oh my god.
Okay, so wait.
Uh, north is that way.
Wait, I guess I don't know, because I have the camera angle weird.
Basically, I wanna burn in the direction I'm kinda pointing.
So that way.
So be...
To be along the plane.
Of the system.
So like, here.
Which means like, there.
But how will I know?
I guess we just blast off and see...
Which way it's pointing.
Okay, you ready?
Here we go.
Nope, not that way, not that way.
That way, that way.
This way.
Okay.
There's plenty of fuel.
Are we aligned?
Kinda.
Wait, hold on.
Let me see the orbit.
Wait, I should have burned the other way.
Fuck, whatever.
It's fine.
Dude, the gravity is so much lower here.
Look at this.
We're already at 20 kilometers from just that.
And this engine is weak.
It's a weak boy.
Okay, when I reach there, I'm gonna...
Wait, I guess that would be...
I need to rotate this.
I can't.
Actually, let me rotate it this way.
Okay.
Let's wait.
Dude, fucking easy so far.
Fucking textbook here.
Valentina, once again.
Jebediah is smiling.
Wherever he is right now.
He's witnessing.
Okay.
Okay, we're actually getting a little low on fuel here.
I don't like that.
Okay, it's not great.
We should have...
There's actually a lot.
Good enough for me.
So check it out.
The spacecraft plus moon system is moving this way around the Earth, right?
Which means whenever we leave the Earth's sphere of...
Sorry, the moon sphere of influence.
We are obviously still gonna be in orbit around Curvan.
It's just gonna be a different one.
It's gonna be a more elliptical one, right?
Or eccentric, I guess.
So basically, we wanna burn this way.
Right?
So we wanna leave the...
Let me think.
Yeah, we wanna burn this way, so we wanna burn on this side.
Holy shit, we be speeding.
Look at this.
Oh-ho-ho!
So where's the Earth?
It's there.
So we should be burning...
Right...
Here.
So we're burning Prograde now.
Turn around, you fat boy.
Ooh, you a thick one.
Valentina?
Hit it!
All we need is escape velocity from...
The moon.
Hmm.
Maybe there's a better way to do this.
This is not a great...
Angle here, I gotta be honest.
This is not good.
I miscalculated this.
Actually, maybe it would've been better to burn on this side...
And let the escape happen this way.
Maybe that's what makes more sense.
Hmm.
Or we just give it some more juice.
Nice!
Never mind, I'm right.
Ha-ha!
There we go.
That's...
That's beautiful.
Whoa, what's happening here?
We have two...
Wait, what's happening here?
The physics engine is bugging!
It doesn't know what to do!
Don't worry, I have it under control.
Oh, wait, we're at a super weird angle, too.
Oops.
Maybe it's okay.
Let's just wait until we leave the Sphere of Influence, see what happens.
Oh, I see what's happening!
When we come back around...
We have another moon encounter!
It's gonna be...
Oh, that's cool!
So at the time we're all the way back here, the moon will have moved all the way around, and it's gonna be...
Right there!
That's so funny!
Ah-ha!
That's cool, man!
Okay, well, here we go.
And...
Nice.
Now, a reasonable man would go here at Apoapsus and start burning.
But I'm not a reasonable man.
And, you know what, Valentina has been in orbit for too long already.
We're burning now.
Uh, retrograde.
The thing I'm a little worried about, though, is we're gonna come in with this service bay.
Uh...
And we're gonna come in hot.
And I do remember with Bob, we had some issues with the stability of this.
But now we do have a stability assist, right?
So we'll see how that goes.
Let's...
Yeah.
Let's burn.
I think we had it at...
40 last time, and it was good.
Oof.
You know what?
We can play this mega safe.
Nah, I don't wanna do that.
Do I wanna do that?
Let me think.
Mmm...
Nah, it's gonna be fine.
We're gonna come in at a very shallow angle.
It's fine.
Okay?
Now, be careful with the time fast-forward here.
Oh, god.
Look at that in the view.
Oh, wow.
Hold on.
I need to see this.
Angle it like...
That.
And then...
Like that.
Almost nailed it.
One last view of...
Kerbin.
Cheers, guys.
Wow.
Like, Kerbin really is a beautiful planet here.
Definitely the most beautiful planet so far.
Can't wait to see the other planets.
Be very careful with the fast-forward.
It's been almost three days already on this mission.
No, it's like two days, actually.
Let's keep it at 100, because we're gonna speed up, too.
Time to point retrograde.
Wait.
I could also detach now, actually.
But we don't have to do that yet.
And chill a little bit.
Whoa.
250.
Oh, my god.
What a view.
What a way to come home as well.
And we're gonna be...
We're gonna land on the bright side and everything.
Oh, man.
That's so good.
Beautiful.
180.
70.
Maybe we detach now?
Let's do it.
Three.
Two.
One.
Bye-bye.
Okay.
Let's see if this shape can, uh...
make it through the atmosphere.
At 3,000 meters per second.
And it's gonna be more than that when we finally reach the atmosphere.
We're gonna reach, like, 3,200, I think.
It's gonna be fast.
Valentina's excited.
You better keep your hand on that stick, darling.
We're entering the atmosphere.
Okay, Valentina.
Shit got serious.
Focus now.
Maximum lockage.
Lock in.
It's getting slightly hot already.
Oh, my God!
Are the landing lights burning off?
What's happening?
Rip, rip, rip.
Hopefully none of that debris is gonna hit me.
See ya.
Oh, God.
We're coming in real fast.
Whoa!
Holy shit!
Yeah, that thing is...
burning up!
Hopefully that's not gonna be me.
Jesus Christ.
There's no heat shield on those parts.
Only on my part.
Thankfully.
Dude, we haven't even slowed down that much yet.
Wow.
I'm glad that this bar is not moving right now.
Hey, look at that.
A blader.
It's not...
Dude, we're fine.
The only thing I'm worried about now is potentially flipping over.
Like, look at this thing.
It's flipping slightly.
Oh, shit.
Valentina!
Fucking...
Hold the stick!
If we flip over, it's game over!
You better hold it!
Oh, my God.
Fuck.
I'm helping.
I'm also holding.
We're both holding.
Why are we not slowing down, man?
Come on!
Fuck!
Oh!
Oh, it's really wanting to turn over.
Jesus.
Oh, God.
Jesus Christ.
Why are you like this?
Why does it want to do that?
Oh, it's moving away.
Please slow down.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
That's good.
Good, good, good, good, good, good.
Dude, I thought we were gonna lose everything.
I mean, we may still, but let's focus.
Wait, are we taking another trip around?
Oh, God.
Oh, shit, we may actually take another trip around.
Oh, man.
This is a questionable re-entry.
We're leaving the atmosphere now slightly.
That's not good.
APWAPS is 126 kilometers.
Yeah, we're coming back around.
Maybe that's for the best.
Whoop.
Camera's flipping.
I guess depending on the height, that's when the camera starts flipping.
So why is this thing not wanting to center on retrograde?
Huh.
I turned off SAS as well.
It's almost like this is the most...
Wait, maybe it's because I've...
Maybe if I turn it slightly.
I can't even do that.
Wait, why not?
Wait, the reaction wheels are not working.
I lost something here.
Electric charge?
I guess you need that for the...
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
We have a problem.
We have a problem here.
We have to turn this...
We have to turn this around.
Uh.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
We're in orbit, right?
Oh, shit.
Guys, we may have to flip this manually.
When we reach Apoapsis, I'm gonna make it flip around from outside.
This is gonna be so ridiculous.
We're gonna have to wait.
96 kilometers.
Dude, this is...
This is why you need batteries!
What the fuck?
Oh, no!
Why don't they have a little treadmill in there I can, you know, exercise in and recharge?
I have an idea, though.
So, we're gonna come into the atmosphere approximately here, right?
Okay, so actually...
Guys, what happened was...
Valentina wasn't even controlling the craft on the way in.
It was actually aerodynamically stable.
From that angle.
So, all we need to do is to have it oriented like that.
And the aero forces will take care of the rest.
So, that's the only thing we need to make sure, is happening.
And we're gonna enter, like...
So, this is Apoapsis...
11...
So, what is this, like 50 here-ish?
Oh, God.
We basically have to turn it 180.
Wish me luck!
Valentina!
Your fucking life is on the line.
You ready?
It's turning.
Holy shit.
And then when it's turned the other way, we gotta bump it...
...to stabilize it.
I'm afraid to bump it again right now.
Because we could easily end up in a...
...uncontrolled spin.
Wait, I just had a ridiculous idea.
Guys, if this is not gonna work...
...I have a genius idea.
It's really dumb.
Looks good!
But check it out.
The way we could actually get out of this...
...is to burn Prograde with my...
...with my Kerbal right now.
And just stay in orbit with my Kerbal.
But I believe.
I believe in this.
I think this will work.
We gotta get in without bumping it now.
Is it still turning?
No, it's because we're orbiting...
...and it looks like...
...it's just an optical illusion.
Crap.
Oh, God.
Wait, hold on.
The last time I can turn it...
...is gonna be around 70 kilometers.
Before that...
...or after that, we can't.
So we have to make sure the...
...wait, we're not oriented right!
We have to turn it sideways!
Oh, shit!
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
This is so bad!
No!
It's out of control already!
Oh, there's no way we can do this!
Okay, it's turning.
Now we gotta...
...stop turning soon.
I think, like, now?
Bump!
Oh, it's turning a little too much this way now.
Bump it!
Are we stable?
Let's turn it from this side now.
Wait, hold on.
I need to see this.
So we're currently angled like that.
Oh, god.
I can't...
I can't fucking predict!
I can't predict!
We may be cooked.
Literally.
Oh, shit.
Wrong way.
We have plenty of propellant.
Now bump here.
Up, up, up, up, up, up, up.
There we go.
Is it stable?
It looks pretty good.
Fuck it.
Get in, get in, get in.
Oh, god.
We're approaching the dark side.
Okay, we're spinning.
That's fine.
Spin is okay.
No, we're still turning...
But then again.
I gotta get out.
Get in.
Uh-oh.
Music stopped.
We're going into the atmosphere.
I can't...
I can't leave the...
I can't leave the aircraft.
No, we're gonna...
We're gonna be bulleting!
It's over.
There's no way.
Please spin around before we hit...
Proper air.
Come on, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin.
Oh, my god.
Come on, yeah.
Keep spinning.
Yes.
It's stabilizing!
Fuck!
We gotta get out!
It's starting to heat!
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
This...
Oh, no.
This is over!
Oh, shit!
Fuck this.
Oh, get it.
Get it.
Oh, we're overheating.
Oh, fuck me, dude.
No!
No, no, no.
Not like this.
It's...
Is it...
It's turning?
What's happening?
No, it's super stable.
Oh, fuck it, dude.
I'm still trying to control it, even though I know I can't.
Oh, no.
No.
The parachutes are cooked, though.
Oh, shit.
No.
Can't...
Transmit!
We don't have a fucking...
Oh, no.
I can't watch this!
I can't watch it.
I can't watch.
Fuck.
I can't do it.
Jesus, take the wheel.
Oh, my God.
Valentina!
All the science!
The moon!
No!
There's so much science on this!
It's absolutely crazy.
I
don't want to see it!
I don't want to see that!
Ah, crap!
Man,
it's fucked.
We're fucked.
Are we?
No, don't give...
Don't give Valentina hope.
It's over.
We're done.
There's no way we survive this.
Oh, no.
We're not even slowing down.
This is the problem.
And we're going into denser...
Ah, we're overheating like fucking crazy, bro.
Ah...
Turns out a bullet shape is pretty good at penetrating air without slowing down.
Oh, man.
Oh,
man.
Valentina, stop smiling like an idiot.
Will you?
You're about to die.
Dude, we have slowed down like 100 meters per second.
Oh, what is that?
Something else is overheating now.
Everything is overheating.
How are we not cooked yet?
What?
Don't give me hope.
No, we're done.
We're done.
It's over.
It's so over.
The heat meter is going up, up, up, up, up.
It's going more and more up.
The parachute is overheating.
Oh, there's a mountain, too.
There's a big old mountain in the way!
What the fuck, bro?
Dude, look at this!
The altimeter is lying.
Not the mountains!
Shit!
Pursuit!
Come on, be yellow, be yellow!
Ah!
Call me crazy.
If that mountain wouldn't have been there, we may have survived.
We were slowing down.
The fucking mountain!
We crashed at, like, nine kilometers?
Or something?
We would have had plenty?
Wow!
That's nuts.
Wait, what?
Wait, oh, yeah, by the way, how do I even do this?
Oh, I didn't even try to click on the stones.
I'm an idiot.
Oh, my God.
I totally forgot.
I mean, not that it matters now, but, you know.
So, wait, what happened here?
Oh!
This counts!
Hey!
That's pretty good.
At least we got this one done.
For some reason, I thought we had to come back, but okay.
Valentina died for that contract.
She set a record.
She did.
Now it's all up to...
What's his name again?
Vasquez?
No.
Carson.
Carson is our only pilot we have left.
That's nuts, man.
Okay, well...
I have learned a massive lesson from that.
A massive lesson.
Absolutely incredible lesson.
We need batteries.
Fucking hell, bro.
Oh!
Wow!
Are you kidding me?
Let's put him in here.
Hey, that's pretty cool.
We can put him like that.
In fact...
No, you dummy!
Why?
Are you...
Oh!
There we go.
Oh, that's...
That's almost too...
Perfect?
Look at that.
That's beautiful.
Whoops.
Hoi!
Okay, well...
Actually, I need to check something.
100 electric charge?
How much do I have in here?
50!
Okay.
Well, okay.
Alright, alright, alright, alright.
Um...
Oh, no, wait.
Oh, shit.
We're out of...
We can't do it.
We can only bring one battery pack.
Ah, I don't want to risk that.
Huh.
You gotta be kidding me here.
Can we do with three landing legs?
Why does it...
I guess I have to press X.
Honestly, three is...
Four is...
Four's gotta be the number here.
Actually, just...
Put it back where we were.
There we go.
Uh, we're one part over budget here.
But honestly, this rocket was amazing.
Like, we did...
Crazy well.
All things considered.
Also, I need to go look at the contracts before I go.
I guess it doesn't matter.
We can just go back to Space Center.
Yeah.
Perhaps we don't need...
Check it out.
Get rid of those.
Oh, but wait.
This is too small, isn't it?
Except it kinda isn't.
Which is super weird.
Does that actually just work?
Or what?
I mean, that's dumb as hell.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Nope.
Don't like that.
Put it back where we were.
Now, what do I get rid of?
Maybe I just bring one battery pack.
I mean, if 50 got us almost to the end...
150 should be fine, right?
I believe.
It's gonna be fine.
In fact, I don't know when I ran...
I guess...
So when you use SAS...
That's what's using the battery.
Because it's like...
Fly-by-wire.
In a way.
You know, which uses electricity.
I'm surprised this rocket did so well as it did...
Without the little aerodynamic cones on it.
Wait, how am I at 4,700 now?
Wasn't I at 4,900?
I'm so confused.
It can't be that battery.
Can it?
No.
There's no way that would add so much mass.
I have no clue.
We are at exactly 30 parts.
Crazy.
But this rocket was good, though.
Good rocket.
Now we have extra battery.
So, hey, you know what?
Maybe we should just really sparingly use SAS.
That's another way to look at it.
These two.
God, that was so close, man.
Wait, wait.
Save?
I need to look at the contracts.
And this time we're bringing home a Moonstone.
I will not forget.
Science data from space around the moon could be good.
Or, what's this?
Rendezvous two vessels in orbit of the moon.
Hold on.
Park two vessels next to each other.
Around the moon.
What could go wrong?
Um...
So, I guess...
Wait, what?
I guess we would, uh...
What?
We would fly one vessel out there and then fly another one in after?
Rescue Landon from orbit of the moon.
What is he doing there?
Landon, how did you get...
Into the orbit of the moon and then...
What on earth?
Somehow this one is...
Giving a lot of stars.
Yeah, we gotta take this one, I think.
It's like an easy one.
Send science data from space around the moon.
Okay.
I can do that.
And you know what?
This time we're gonna bring a, uh...
What do you call it?
A...
Uh...
The thing that sends...
Transmits data.
We want that.
Yeah.
Give me that.
Which means we're gonna modify this slightly.
Let's see here.
That would be communication.
Let's do a high-gain antenna.
I like that.
I guess we can put it on this module, since we're gonna...
Discard it anyway later.
Can I...
There we go.
Let's put it, like, here so we don't block the opening of the...
Of this here.
It looks so cool.
Oh.
Sweet.
I wonder if you have to angle the aircraft as well.
To actually get proper communication.
Uh...
Anything else?
Oh, wait.
This probably costs electricity, right?
Fuck, wait, we're over.
I can't bring it.
I can't do it, Captain.
Shit.
We gotta upgrade this facility so we can have more parts.
That's gotta be, like, the next big thing that we get.
Okay.
Here we are.
Carson.
The OGs are dead.
It's up to you now.
I believe.
We've done it before.
You've learned...
From what they did.
Except you haven't.
Because we haven't transmitted any information.
And we didn't bring any information back.
But...
We were probably on the radio somehow anyway.
Just talking to, you know...
Mission control.
Is what I imagine.
Gonna start turning...
Oh my...
Why does this rocket want to...
Rotate so bad?
Why is that?
Stop.
Stop rotating.
Man, I'm holding down the rotation button.
Just to counteract whatever rotation's happening here.
Hoi yoi yoi.
It still wants to rotate.
Let's try and do this even better now.
So we're at 75 on Apoapsis.
Let's go a little more horizontal here.
Looking good.
Looking pretty good.
In fact, I'm gonna burn up there instead.
With this engine.
So we're at...
We're gonna probably be at...
A thousand when we're up there.
So we're gonna have to burn for a while.
I'm gonna say almost a minute.
Let's say a minute.
We're gonna wait a little more here.
Wait.
Let's burn now.
Burn now.
Man, the atmosphere is just stellar.
No pun intended.
You know what?
We can afford to burn a little later here.
Right here.
Let me turn off SAS.
Preserve electricity.
How much do I have now?
Can I...
Just...
Quickly...
Wait, we still...
Wait, we have 150?
Wait, how?
How the hell?
Okay.
We're in orbit.
How do we not use any?
Wait, look.
It's like...
Oh, wait.
Is this showing me how much I'm using per second or something?
It was going up and down just now.
So if I turn...
Oh, yeah.
Look!
If I...
If I use SAS...
You see that?
If I turn it off...
Oh, wait.
I guess it's still...
Oh, of course.
Because the reaction wheels are still working.
Of course.
So whether or not I do it or Valentina...
Or in this case, Carson does it.
Valentina.
It's still going to consume electricity, right?
Because the reaction wheels are spinning.
I see how that is.
Okay, you bastard.
I'm coming for you.
So the moon is there.
So...
I've got this now.
So it's like...
There.
Which means...
Right before the space center.
But let's not forget...
The moon is going to move.
Whoa!
We're actually there.
Prograde.
Oh, my God.
It's so thick and heavy.
Wow.
146 electric charge already.
Ooh.
I am glad...
I figured that out.
And we brought extra.
Wait, what?
Oh, wait.
Burning the engine...
Uh...
Restores electricity?
There's got to be like an alternator in there then, or something.
Just like a car, you know?
If you drive it, you...
Refill the battery.
Oh, my God.
Look at this.
Honestly, I like it.
I like this, uh...
Yeah, I like it.
Maybe.
No, I like it.
I like it even more...
Oh, no.
I did the same thing again.
Oh, my God.
God damn it.
Retrograde.
Oh, my God.
You're so...
Massive.
Come on, turn, you bastard.
I'm gonna have to just slightly adjust this.
Sometimes when I want to increase it a little bit, I accidentally hit C on the keyboard.
And it just goes full power.
Okay, good enough now.
I like it.
Good.
Now we fast forward.
Come on, Carson.
This is your moment!
Moon intercept course.
Calm down a bit.
Speed up a bit.
Sphere of influence.
Now.
It's automatically slowing down before this happens.
Okay, so check it out.
The sun is there.
So this is actually not great.
I do want to get closer first.
We're gonna go all the way to periapsis, actually.
So that we can land on the lit side.
Let me see, uh, battery.
So look, 140 now.
But as soon as I start burning...
Let's wait a bit more.
There.
Oh, that was that engine!
Oh, shit!
Hey, what happened?
The SAS cannot even keep up?
Wait, what's going on?
Why are you wanting to point that way?
What's happening?
Stop.
Detach.
Look at this.
This may be my favorite part of the game, actually.
Just getting out here and looking at this stuff.
Let's turn retrograde.
And we are way less massive now, so no problem turning.
Let's see the electric charge go up when we burn.
Oh, I can't burn from the map?
The, uh...
Wait, never mind.
It's not going up.
What the fuck?
Huh.
Maybe I'm wrong.
How did I just get electric charge, then?
I am confused.
Maybe it updates that...
No?
Okay, that's weird.
I like it.
Then when we get here, we're going to start burning heavily.
Whoa.
That was actually a beautiful time warp there.
Dude, let's...
Let's land in the crater!
Dude, I can barely see the crater from here, because it's so big.
You can kind of tell, though.
Damn.
Much more visible from the...
Oh, look!
Look at the moon peaking!
I mean, curving.
Extend the legs.
Wow!
That's amazing.
Imagine, humans have seen this view in real life.
Isn't that mind-blowing to think about?
It's honestly crazy.
Okay, let's not burn all the fuel up here.
We want to be a little faster when we burn.
It's more efficient.
I do want to land inside of here, though.
I don't know if I should land inside that crater.
That's maybe a little too crazy.
Let's do this.
I think I did better with fuel last time.
I'm not 100% sure.
Speeding up slightly.
Valentina, you better point retro.
There we go.
I'm keeping an eye on this electric charge, man.
This is a new freaking fear I have developed.
It looks kind of flat, doesn't it?
But you can't really tell.
So wait, hold on.
We need an emergency procedure here.
If it's not flat when we approach, we need to get out.
Like, we just turn on the engine to max.
That's like the abort criteria.
Because last time, it didn't even look like it was hilly.
Or, like, tilted, but it was.
I have no idea if this is flat.
I guess we'll find out.
Okay, here we go.
Looking good.
Carson, you are doing it.
Now, is it...
I guess I can zoom out like this and check.
Oh, it looks relatively flat, doesn't it?
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
This is not flat terrain.
I want to land here.
Oh, god.
This better be okay.
Please be okay.
Where are we gonna land?
Looks like...
Oh, shh.
Tell me it's just aesthetic.
It's just aestheticism.
It's not real.
Looks like we're coming in right between the rocks here.
I'm ready on the trigger.
Are we good?
Fuck
me, dude.
I'm so scared.
I am so ready to take off at a moment's notice.
Get the signs and get out.
Wait, I guess we still have the flag on the moon, don't we?
The flag should still be there.
That's fucking awesome, actually.
The goo is happy to be on the far side of anything, especially if it isn't actively crashing into it.
That's 24 in the bag.
And we have the temperature.
Between the dusty atmosphere and the reduced light in the crater, it is difficult to read the thermometer.
Good.
122 electric charge.
We're chilling.
This battery is doing wonders.
The pressure gauge is sitting there motionless.
Perhaps you should tap it a few times to be sure.
Nope, nothing's happening.
Okay, then this guy.
As you look away, one sample makes a run for it.
But I catch it.
Okay, now we gotta transfer data.
To that.
And...
I guess we can transfer here as well.
Yeah, actually.
Transfer.
So wait, I wonder.
Now that we did this...
Um...
We can actually go up into orbit and take more science.
Because we can have science on us in the pot, and then there's science in here.
We can't do this one, though, because this one needs to be reset.
And we need a scientist for that.
Close doors.
Speaking of, we need science in orbit.
From space around the moon, right?
Okay, so wait.
Bring a moonstone back.
We gotta do this.
Are we stable?
I am not gonna...
Time forward here anymore.
I learned my lesson.
You know what?
I'm actually not trusting these to be open.
Close them.
Okay, wait.
I'm gonna let go.
I'm gonna RCS.
Up.
Beautiful.
So wait, how do I take a stone?
Maybe I need to stand on it and then...
EVA report anyway.
A small rock cracks your visor!
You begin to question EVA on a surface with no atmosphere.
In that case...
Activate the extra visor.
Ha ha ha.
Crap.
What?
Actually, don't...
Do not bump into that.
I'm so afraid of this.
How do I take a...
Moonstone?
Maybe I need, like, the EVA experiments kit or something.
I don't know.
We need to plant the flag, by the way.
I'm gonna do it right here.
Right here.
There we go.
Beautiful.
Uh, we're gonna call this...
Valentina...
Landing.
In honor...
Of the brave hero that is Valentina...
Who paved the way...
For this space program...
To succeed.
Rest in peace.
There we go.
Okay, let's...
Let's get...
Let's back...
Back in the rocket before anything goes wrong.
I'm getting pretty good at this, though.
Give me the prompt.
Okay, so now...
We want to go...
This way.
Does that make sense?
Maybe.
But I don't know where I am.
That's the problem.
Like, the angle is fucking with me.
Okay, here we go.
You ready?
Jackie is underneath me right now.
She's wanting to jump up, I think.
I'm so scared.
Jackie, please don't.
Don't fuck with me right now, please.
This is an important moment.
SAS.
Oh!
We bumped out the rock!
You saw that?
This way, this way, this way.
I hope I'm actually doing...
Yeah, we're on the actual angle.
Good, good, good.
Sweet.
Looking good.
We have a lot of fuel.
Stop.
Let's see.
Are we sort of aligned?
Oh, it's beautiful!
Oh, it was the perfect direction, man.
Very...
In fact, we may just burn enough here for escape velocity immediately.
Is that...
Is that smart?
Let me think.
Actually, it's not.
We're gonna burn over here, that way.
And I think last time, the reason it fucked up was because we burned this way when we went this way around.
Which is not really what we want...
Wait.
I guess...
Wait, I guess at the time we start burning, we're gonna have moved.
Uh...
Yeah, I...
Yeah.
We're gonna...
We're gonna try this.
I think I have it.
I'm gonna wait until we are approaching Apoapsis.
A little more.
Health battery.
Doing great.
Prograde.
Retract legs.
We're going for the earth!
I mean, carbon.
Look at that.
Man, that's a screenshot right there.
Wow.
There we go.
I think I burned a little too late.
I got...
I got a little bit, uh...
Preoccupied with...
With the, um...
With the view there.
Electric charge.
Yeah, I see how this works.
So we were at 100...
Or, like, we would have had 11 left at this point.
You know?
Okay, so now we want to burn here.
So that we get escape trajectory this way.
But we're actually burning that way.
So if you think about it...
Imagine us being in an orbit around earth right now.
Right?
Oh, wait, wait.
Actually.
Let me think about this.
So if we're in orbit around earth...
Right, and this is the thing that looks like that.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, we want to burn exactly here.
That's it.
Wonderful.
I got it.
Watch.
This is going to put us on a great trajectory towards earth.
Right here.
Prograde.
Okay, let me try and explain what I'm thinking here.
This circle right now represents the orbit that I am on with my vessel right now around Kerbin.
Right?
And if I was around this only and there was no moon I would burn this way, right?
To reduce the periapsis over here down.
Which is effectively what I'm doing by burning this way now.
That's why.
Oh, the alignment is perfect.
See that?
Can do more.
42.
Okay, last time we did 40 and it was not enough.
33.
Here we go.
It's been one day and four hours on this mission since launch.
Wait!
I forgot something!
I forgot science around the moon.
We have fuel left.
Ah, shit.
Dang it.
Dude, I did none of these!
And what about the moonstone?
Oh my god.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What did I even do here then?
Wait, maybe I'm technically still in space above the moon or something.
Let me try.
This one we can't do.
Let's try...
Because the moon is right there, no?
I mean...
Yeah!
Oh, recover.
So we need to bring it back.
That's why I didn't do anything yet.
Perfect.
This probably counts then.
It does say 0.0.
Ugh.
Not that good.
But you know what I can try?
EVA.
Let go.
I'm going to try to deposit my EVA report from earlier.
I don't know if I can do that.
Oh, shit.
I can't.
I can only take data.
Aw, man.
Dang it.
Hey, but I can do this!
The view of the mountains below is much clearer when you're not looking through a window of a spaceship.
Hey, there we go.
We got it.
Where did I exit?
There.
Dude, I'm an EVA master now.
There we go.
Okay, now.
We wait for...
Carbon.
That's pretty much all it is.
It's just a waiting game now.
And electric charge is looking good.
It's not even going down.
Whoa,
slow down.
We're making it, guys.
This is it.
We got electric charge.
It's beautiful.
Carson is doing what Valentina couldn't.
But not because Valentina couldn't do it.
It was the engineers back home that fucked her.
They were the ones who didn't bring batteries.
It wasn't Valentina.
She is not at fault.
She was at the mercy of the engineers.
Damn engineers.
Retrograde.
Oh, let's also close this up, shall we?
There we go.
Don't want those experiments to burn up on the way back.
I'm going to burn a little more.
Let's take it to 30.
There's no way we're not going to land now.
Like, no way.
Okay, you ready?
Three, two, one.
Wonderful.
Let's do the same dance as last time.
We got electric charge.
Nice.
106 left.
That's plenty.
Carson, you glorious bastard.
Here we go.
Okay.
Focus up.
Put those snacks away.
Grab the handle.
We're entering the atmosphere.
This is very familiar.
I hope this deja vu doesn't actually replicate all the way.
Dude, some of this could blast off and hit my vessel.
What happens then?
Holy shit.
I mean, look at that, bro.
See ya.
So dope.
Uh-oh.
Okay, I thought the game just crashed, man.
Please don't fuck with me now.
Please let me get to the ground.
Let me get to the ground safely here.
We are slowing down.
Much faster.
And we're already at 30.
Okay, that's good.
Good.
So far, so good.
We are gonna be in darkness, maybe.
It's gonna be right on the Terminator.
Nah, we're gonna be in darkness, because we're also turning, remember?
The carbon is turning.
Thunderstorm's over there.
It's looking good.
God, it's so pretty.
Look at that, man.
Oh my god!
How does this game keep surprising me with these views?
I can't get enough.
Oof.
Time for parachute soon.
I see grassland below us.
Drogues are up.
This is looking like a home run.
But let's not eat the snacks before they're bought.
Anything could happen.
Dude, what if there's aliens in this game?
Actually, I hadn't considered that.
Maybe there's like...
Alien lifeforms on some other planets or something.
You know, like plants or...
Whatever.
Planet in the sky.
Jewel.
Why is it always jewel?
That's in the sky there.
Okay, it's time for...
Main chute.
Beautiful.
Oh, it's so...
That looks so scary over there.
I'd rather look this way.
It's much nicer.
Yep, that's dark.
Drogues deployed.
Fully deployed.
Let's speed it up slightly here.
Wait, this is a different area now.
Look.
This is not the desert.
Man, what a trip.
What a trip.
I don't think anything can go wrong now.
Like, we nailed it.
This is it.
It doesn't get better than this.
I can't wait to use the science we got.
Oh, we got so much science too.
Please don't hit a tree.
Wait, wait, wait.
Can something go wrong?
Please.
Oh.
Oh my goodness.
Oh my fucking goodness.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, we made it.
We made it.
Wow.
Okay.
228 science.
What the fuck?
And 400,000 dollarinos in my pocket renos.
Five experience gain.
But we haven't even gotten a second star.
Wow.
Warp to sunrise.
Huh.
Man, you deserve eggs and bacon, Carson.
You have done it, man.
Except the...
Wait.
Let me read this.
Find a moonstone, have a kerbal pick it up, and return it to Kerbin.
We suspect you can find one of these in the polar lowlands.
Fuck.
Why didn't I fucking read this shit?
Farside crater or east crater biomes.
Wait, how do I know which biome I'm in?
Oh, okay.
So that's why I...
I guess I wasn't here?
Oh my god.
I need to learn to read this freaking quest here.
Are you kidding me?
Plant a...
I already planted a flag.
I planted two flags.
Don't do this.
Explore Minmush.
Science data from the surface now.
Okay.
Dude, are you ready?
Before we take any assignments, it's research and development time.
Let's see what we want!
Oh my god, 228 science.
Are you kidding me?
We are rich!
We can get anything we want!
Okay, so hold on.
What is all this?
EVA?
Fuck that.
I don't know what that is.
Conformal storage unit?
Hitchhiker storage container.
Crew capacity 4!
Oh my god, that's what we need to...
Transport Kerbals.
Maybe this is what I take.
I really want this.
Stack separator.
Some kind of adapter.
Go op ED monitor?
What would happen if you left some mystery goo sitting around in the weird radiation and or atmosphere of some faraway planet?
It's a thought that has occurred to nearly every Kerbal.
And now you can find out thanks to the intrepid engineers at Floyd.
Please allow trained scientists to deploy for best results.
Also note, please do not return to Kerbin.
Ever!
What?
Needs a deployed power unit and central station to operate.
Wait, so this is something we put on another body?
I guess it's gonna give me science.
This must give me a lot.
Clampatron docking port?
I don't want to buy stuff from these guys.
Fuck Clampatron, man.
But wait a second.
Docking port sounds pretty damn cool.
Interstellar docking scene, man.
Photovoltaic panels.
Rechargeable battery bank!
The C200 is a stackable variant of the C100 battery pack.
With increased capacity, in emergency situations, please refrain from reversing the polarity.
Yeah, you never want to do that.
Or cross the streams.
Okay, okay, okay.
Flight control.
Small inline reaction wheel.
What's this?
Advanced stabilizer.
Lander can!
This capsule was designed for lightweight, non-atmospheric landers.
Ooh.
Place anywhere linear RCS port.
I want RCS!
Mark II command pod.
Crew capacity is two on this one!
I feel like we need this.
This may actually be...
the most important thing.
So that's 45 and 90.
135.
So let's say we get that.
Landing.
These must be bigger.
I guess.
Maybe longer.
Launch escape system?
I mean...
Are rockets ever gonna malfunction, though?
I feel like they always just work.
I mean, it's not like real life, where sometimes, you know, they just fucking blow up.
And if they do blow up, you don't have time to react anyway.
Then you're cooked.
Oh my god.
There's so many cool things!
Okay, let's say this is locked in.
We're taking these two.
Because I want this.
And let's say we do that.
And then what?
Spark liquid fuel engine.
Ant liquid fuel engine.
Mass point...
Are these like mini-freaking engines?
What is this?
An engine for ants?
Cannot research technologies over a hundred signs at this level.
Oh!
Okay, I guess we gotta upgrade, then.
But that's gonna cost.
Actually, I like that!
Means we can focus on all this first.
Advanced construction, maybe?
What's this?
General construction.
Mark 1 crew cabin.
Wait, TD points...
Tell me this is a bigger version.
Because I would love that, actually!
Actually, there's a bunch of these.
Look!
This has to be it.
I feel like we should take this, too.
It's only 45.
So what's that?
That's one...
That's like 180-ish.
Then we won't have enough for anything else.
Then we can't get this.
But do I need this?
What is this one?
Keeps the expensive and delicate equipment our astronauts need to bring with them safely stored.
Rigorous engineering studies have shown it to be 20% more effective than a picnic cooler and some duct tape at making sure these items arrive intact at their destination.
So is that just not the same as this?
Maybe it's just bigger.
So this is .05.
Also .05.
Cargo storage units.
Oh, man.
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know.
Okay, let's go for this one.
Just the capability of having two Kerbals inside a capsule is insane.
We need this.
We need it.
I'm not going to buy any of this yet.
I want that one.
Okay, so now we have 90 science left.
So it's either one of these big ones or that one.
This one sounds really good because of the decouplers.
But I really want the EVA experiments kit.
Imagine how much more science we're going to get with this.
It's probably going to give a shit ton of science.
You know?
Let me actually read.
Probobodyne has meticulously curated and assembled this case full of various devices useful for science experiments.
Despite observations to the contrary, we feel that the inability of our astronauts to find a good use for the collapsible top hat and magic wand is more to do with a lack of creativity rather than a case of them being left over from prior use.
These Kerbals are kind of silly, aren't they?
Silly Kerbals.
So wait.
This is called a stack separator.
What the hell is the difference between that and a decoupler?
I'm not sure.
Electrics.
Dude!
Oh, wait.
Solar panels are going to keep me topped up on electricity.
Oh, I want that now, actually.
But then again, having batteries kind of offset that problem just now.
And I had lots left over, you know?
I think I'm going to take...
Actually, we can take two of these.
We can take this one and that one.
But do I even want this?
Let me see.
This is like airplane stuff.
I don't care about airplanes.
Is it going to lead to anything?
It's going to lead to more airplane stuff?
Yeah, this is airplane stuff.
Why would you...
Oh, supersonic flight.
Okay, maybe it is useful later, but right now, I don't really care.
I got to be honest.
I'm going to take this.
Bomb.
I got it.
Yep.
I need to see something, though.
I want to see these decouplers in action.
Wait, engine plate.
Uh...
Inspired by an upside-down birthday cake, but with added shrouds for windy days.
for clustering multiple small engines on small tanks.
Oh, so...
Instead of just having one engine down here, you can have, like, multiple on one sort of part.
That's kind of cool.
So, yeah, if you want, like...
You have a big surface area here, you can add lots of smaller ones, but...
Yeah, okay.
That's cool.
Let me try this one.
Oh, my God, yes!
Yes!
What about that one?
Oh, yeah!
Oh, my God!
Guys, we're gonna make the craziest rockets with this.
And we also...
What else did I get?
I got something else.
Oh, yeah, all of this stuff.
Oh, oh!
That one!
Oh, wait, shit!
Is it bigger?
Oh, I thought it was the same size!
And there was just, you know, they crammed two people in there.
Oh, no!
Actually, maybe it's not that bad.
Because we actually have engines for this size, right?
Actually, it's not that bad.
Wait, hold on.
New rocket.
Don't save.
This is now the basis.
And then...
Parachute.
We always want this.
The thing is, though, is one parachute gonna be enough now?
Since this is a bigger buoy, you know?
It weighs more.
Hmm.
Maybe we need some, uh, radial...
normal parachutes, too.
Non-drogue ones.
Okay.
You know what we're gonna do?
We're gonna take one of these...
here.
And then we're gonna test.
We're gonna try just this first with these two drogues.
And see if it's enough.
Oh, wait.
Let me see what the impact thing is on this.
Four...
Okay, 14 meters per second.
That's...
That's quite high, isn't it?
Same as that one.
So, if it's not enough, we just deploy this one.
This is like a safety chute.
Like...
Wait.
I guess all chutes are safety chutes.
Ha ha ha!
In a way.
Um...
Okay.
Then we need the...
Oh, shit.
Wait.
I think we may need a bigger one here.
Oh, fuck me, dude.
Wait, wait, wait.
Uh...
Test.
Save it.
Uh-oh.
Tell me they must exist, right?
Would that be here?
Landing.
2.5...
Yeah, it's gotta be.
Fuck.
Fuck!
Why didn't I take this?
Oh, I suck!
Fuck!
God!
I didn't even think about that!
Then again, if I had taken this, I wouldn't have had this.
Actually, yeah, if I had taken this, I would have looked at this and gone, Oh, fuck!
Why didn't I do that?
You know?
So, it's fine.
We just need a little bit more science.
We can do that.
Maybe there's a different way to...
Oh, God.
Now, I hate this now.
No, man.
I wonder.
Maybe one is enough.
Wait, is that the actual hatch where you exit and enter?
That can't be right.
Wait, what?
No, this has to be where you...
You see that outline there?
Because this is going to be part of the rocket.
How are you going to exit?
Oh, maybe it's here, actually, because there's handles.
Maybe there's a little way to...
Wait, what?
Where's the entrance?
Maybe it's this little sliver.
I have no idea, bro.
How do you get in?
Wait, we need a quick test here.
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Oh, look.
There's two people inside.
I'm just going to...
We're going to test to see how we can actually exit.
I'm so curious.
Well, there you go.
You sort of spawn.
But maybe that's like a little weird.
Okay, well.
All right.
There you go.
Got it.
Mystery solved.
Not too bad.
Okay, well.
I like that.
Put these back on.
Two of these.
One of these.
But now is the question.
What on earth do you do now?
I think the answer is we can't use this yet.
Yeah, we're actually fucked.
We can't use that.
Not until we have a heat shield.
Shit.
But hey, we have this now too.
Oh, this one also has two.
Wait, hold on.
Is that the small one?
You can have two people in here.
It's not very aerodynamic, but...
I mean...
Maybe that's fine.
Um...
I really don't like the shape of this.
Why...
Why are you designing this shape?
It doesn't make sense.
This one has a crew capacity of three.
Whoa.
Wait, what is this?
Ultimate solution in crew safety.
Remote receivers.
This device does require electricity to operate.
Oh, wait.
Is this like a...
We don't even need kerbals for this one.
Why would I do that then?
What is this good for?
Why would you ever...
Actually...
I guess if you send up a rover or something...
You would want that to be all...
You know, crew-less.
Yeah, okay.
I see that.
It makes sense.
Yeah.
Dude, I think next up...
We're gonna have to take the contract to go to Minmus.
This is the next logical thing.
Explore Minmus.
And it says what?
Uh...
Sometimes Science throws a curveball.
Flyby Minmus.
Okay, so it's actually just a flyby.
Dude, hell yeah.
We're gonna get science from that.
Let's do that now.
We don't even need this big-ass command pod for that.
I'm taking the good old one.
Actually, I'm gonna bring up my...
My, my, my, my, my thingy.
The moon or white boy.
Since we're not landing, maybe we don't need as much Delta V.
But we are going further out.
So maybe it's fine if we do.
But I do want to kind of redesign this slightly.
Um...
Let's call this...
Minmus...
Uh...
I don't know.
Minmus, uh...
No, uh...
Maximus.
Ha ha ha ha!
I don't know, man.
Uh...
We're just heading there...
To check it out.
Nothing more.
No brave ideas.
We're just going there.
And...
Yeah, we don't need these.
What do I need?
This is total overkill, isn't it?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Watch this, watch this.
We don't need this anymore now.
Because we have the thing.
And then...
Wait.
Hold on.
New idea, new idea.
Let's try...
Oh, wait, we don't even need...
Oh, hold on a minute now.
We don't even need this.
Wait, get rid of all that.
We have new parts now.
Fuck that.
Let's try...
Um...
No, that was too big.
This one.
That looks incredible, man.
Oh, man, look at that.
There's so many.
I like...
I like it.
Nah, I don't like that very much.
I like this.
That looks kind of dope.
No, actually, I hate it.
Yeah.
What is the difference between these?
Wait, white shroud?
Compact?
Oh, yeah.
Okay, let's go compact.
Expose more of the inner workings.
That looks kind of cool in itself.
Now, we do this.
Oh, beautiful.
And now we do...
Uh...
These...
No, that's too big.
Is it these ones?
Is there a bigger version?
No.
Okay.
So, we do two of those.
Three of those.
What engine, though?
Oh, shah.
That's too big.
What if we just do the same one again?
I mean...
Wait, is that stupid as...
Wait, hold on.
That's actually kind of stupid, isn't it?
Is this overkill?
Maybe we're overkilling.
I don't know.
No, we're not.
4,000?
Wait, 4,000 already?
Dude, watch this.
Are you ready?
This is gonna be like...
9...
90,000 delta V.
Nah, not that much.
But it's gonna be a lot.
Almost 6...
Oh, my God.
Almost 6,000 delta V.
What the fuck?
And it's cheaper than the other rocket I made.
Okay, this is definite overkill.
Or is it?
Nah, it's overkill.
Has to be.
What's the thrust to weight?
1.5!
Man, that's pretty good.
I feel like we should try this puppy.
This looks insane.
Let's make it look nice.
Can I change this look?
I can't.
Okay.
I mean, that's...
Why not?
Nah.
Yeah, that's it.
That's it.
Dude, this rocket is kinda neat.
I like the way it looks.
It's very nice.
And it's cheap.
Actually, it's not that cheap.
Call me crazy.
I feel like we could even take off with this.
Let me see the thrust.
Yeah, thrust.
We can do this.
That's 4,000 already.
Isn't that like the exact...
No, wait.
I had 4,800.
Okay, maybe we do need this.
So this one, and then this one, and that one go together.
This one.
That one.
Yep.
Looks good to me.
Minimus Maximus.
Let's do it, man.
Let's go.
I didn't even see who was flying.
Who's flying?
It's Carson.
Okay.
That's fine.
Carson has proven himself.
He can do this.
So...
Oh, wait.
We actually have a problem here, though.
So Minimus is here.
We have no idea how far ahead to aim.
Shit.
I mean, we can just sort of...
I mean...
Actually, if we assume the same angle...
Let's just assume the same angle.
Start somewhere.
So this rocket is much bigger than the other rocket, but it doesn't feel bigger when you look at it from this angle.
Just looks like a good old rocket.
Oh, wait.
I need to...
Oh, I already did.
Good.
I got the quest for Minimus.
Dude, not only are we going to Moon today, we're also going to Minimus.
This is...
Groundbreaking stuff right here.
I'm gonna start turning.
Oh, wait.
I can't.
Never mind.
Dude, we're only half...
Oh, my...
God.
This is way too powerful.
No Kerbal should ever possess this amount of power.
Wow.
And we're moving so fast already.
I'm barely turning.
Separation time.
See ya.
Oh, it's so quiet compared to the other one.
Whoa, I have massive control.
The gimbal is crazy on this.
Okay, let's start turning like crazy.
Oh, our plops.
This is at 110 already.
What the fuck?
We're going straight up and then...
It completely turned 90 degrees.
Whatever.
Wow.
Wait, we're barely moving here.
Like, we're not even moving the dial.
Wow.
We're already at 60?
What the fuck?
Yeah, this is a powerful rocket.
Dude, that's barely making a dent.
Looks cool, though.
That's a cool-looking engine.
A double engine.
What's it called?
Bobcat.
Sweet.
Wait, you can shut down engine via here and thrust limiter.
Huh.
Well, there you go.
Why not just do this instead?
Why do you have to limit the thrust?
I'm just burning continuously on this stage until I have none left.
Who knows?
Maybe we can even get a somewhat stable orbit from this.
I doubt it, though.
It's gonna be a little messy.
I mean...
Running out of fuel in just a couple seconds here.
There we go.
God, the way it emerges.
Look at that.
Guess what?
Another bobcat.
Like the Russian doll.
Okay, so we get to Appleopses, and we burn the shit out of this.
Oh, yeah.
Now, we don't need to burn a lot, either, because we already did a lot of the work here.
In fact, I think this is...
Pretty good.
Prograde.
And action.
Oh, god.
Wow, that was more powerful than I thought.
Okay, so let's see here.
Where are you?
Over there.
Wait, are you sort of...
Oh!
Wait, hold on.
This is...
This means I have to hit it over here, unless I change inclination.
Wait, actually, I was gonna go here anyway.
It's like approximately here anyway, and if we go that way...
We are gonna be at the same sort of...
Plane.
Right over there, if I get there.
Maybe we don't need to change inclination here.
Hmm.
Yeah, yeah.
I think it's good.
That is sound.
Don't go too fast.
Wait, where are you?
There.
God, I hope...
Ugh.
We could completely miss it here.
This is the thing.
Right now, we're sort of aiming...
There.
Oh, god.
Maybe I'm too late.
Actually, start burning now.
Just burn now.
This is gonna increase more and more and more.
So...
Oh, my god.
This is actually going...
Oh!
What?
I think we just had some sort of thing going on there.
Retrograde.
How are we doing on electric?
Oh, we're...
Wait, are we recharging that?
Let me pay attention now.
I'm gonna click on it.
First try, baby.
But wait.
Oh, god.
I wish the camera would...
Wait, so when I'm here...
Minmush is there.
When I...
Wait, when I'm here...
I mean, as long as we're inside the sphere of influence, we can do anything.
Then I'm happy.
I like it.
Okay!
Let's fast forward.
Bye-bye, Kerbin.
We are on the way!
Whoa.
Actually, I need to see this.
Can I see it from here?
Goddamn sun is in the way.
Wait, I can't even see it.
Is that it?
No, that's a star.
No, that's Joule.
It's always Joule.
Ha-ha.
Ah, fuck it.
Whatever.
What's coming from there?
Minmush.
It's moving at 274 meters per second only.
Whoa.
Let's see if we can see it.
Are you here?
Is that it?
No, that's the moon.
Oh, my god.
It's so tiny.
Look at that.
Look how tiny Kerbin is.
Damn.
Why can't I see Minmush?
It's probably in the sun.
Also, it's a little off-axis, right?
So maybe...
It's not that much off-axis.
Dude, what?
Okay, I guess it's tiny as hell, or I'm blind.
We're moving a little faster.
Look, it's the same principle.
We're moving so slow, it's coming into our view now.
Come on, show yourself.
Maybe turn off SAS.
Conserve some electric charge, even though we have a lot.
Dude, is it in the sun?
Maybe it's in the sun.
I legitimately cannot find it, man.
Is that it?
You see that?
See that right there?
You can see the Terminator across it.
That has to be it.
Fast forward.
It's very tiny on this view.
It's getting bigger.
Yep, see it?
Oh!
Oh my god.
Wait, what the fuck is going on here?
Wait, we're getting a kick out of the moon on the way back, it seems.
What the hell?
We need to slow down even more right now.
Because we are not in the sphere of influence, it seems.
Anytime soon.
So hold on.
Let me see this.
Oh, wait, what?
Now it's changed.
What the fuck?
Never mind.
Oh, when you fast forward, it's like not registering.
Oh my god.
Oh!
Oh, look at that.
Look at that.
Where are you?
Oh, look.
Oh, that's definitely tiny.
You can see the little...
It's not perfectly spherical.
That is a tiny-ass moon.
So wait, we are technically at Minmus now.
It's time for some science, but I really gotta take a piss.
I'll be right back, man.
I'm not even gonna pause because, I mean, we're moving so slow.
I'll be back in a second.
All right.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Carson is somehow still excited.
How many...
It's been 10 days on this mission!
Oh my god.
Wow.
Wait a sec.
We actually...
You know what's cool about this?
When we exit Minmus, we're gonna be on the perfect return trip already, without even burning anything.
That's amazing.
Okay, well...
Um...
Let's see here.
I wanna get closer.
Let's go to at least periapsis.
Then we're gonna bring out the Nikon.
Oh, but wait!
That's the dark side!
I can't see shit, then!
Oh, look at that!
Let's have a look.
Whoop, whoop, whoop!
That's a bit too much.
There we go.
Yo, what the hell?
That looks very difficult to land on.
There's something very reflective there.
On the surface.
Oh my god.
Carson is getting to see things that only Jebediah and Valentina could dream of.
This is so nice.
Let's do some science.
Okay.
Crew report.
While in space, high over Minmus.
At this distance, Kerbin is a little more than a pale blue dot floating in the inky vastness of space.
Nice reference to the pale blue dot by Carl Sagan there.
Honestly, I wouldn't call this a pale blue dot.
I would call this a pale blue marble.
At this distance.
But okay.
We keep that.
Let's do some material study here.
Oh my god, we get 37 science from this!
That's insane, man!
The samples react to the lack of an atmosphere.
Sweet!
Oh, we're bringing home the bacon on this one.
Show me the temperature.
Yeah, we can't measure it.
It's 12 science though.
We take that.
18 science from the pressure scan!
Very nice.
And mystery goo.
It's 15.
Just a little bit extra there on top.
You feel like eating the goo.
Of course you do.
You sicko.
I knew Carson was a sicko, man.
I mean, look at him.
Definite psycho.
Okay, transfer data.
There you go.
Transfer data.
Everything gets transferred.
Nice.
And let's also do an EVA report.
Wow.
Floating so peculiarly.
It looks so small.
And yet so delicious.
Wait, is this maybe made of cheese?
Imagine.
That would be so funny.
Or some kind of food, you know?
Bubblegum or whatever it's called.
Mawam.
Okay, we got the EVA report.
Very nice.
And in fact, we don't have to do anything.
We will escape the sphere of influence here very soon.
Close that up.
Let me see here.
So currently...
Apoapsis is at infinity.
I like that.
Or it takes infinitely a long time to get to Apoapsis.
Because we're not gonna get there.
Okay.
Let's just fast forward.
I do want to see this from this view, though.
Where are you?
There you are.
The damn sun.
It's in the way.
God, it's so tiny and mysterious, isn't it?
Now that I look at it, it does look like some kind of chewy candy.
I would put that in my mouth.
If it fit.
Looks like one of those candies where, you know, there's something sour inside the center.
Wow, we are moving so slow.
Bye-bye, Minmus.
Bye-bye.
We are on a hella eccentric orbit here.
Can't wait to see what my periapsis is.
Oh, look!
It's minus 3.9 kilometers!
That's so funny.
We don't have to do anything.
We're getting home like this.
But you know what?
I'm actually not...
Like, this is scaring me, you know?
This feels like we're gonna come home at a crazy speed.
And so, what I suggest we do is that we increase periapsis, of course.
So, oh, how much battery?
Okay, massive battery.
Good.
We're gonna put on SAS.
We're gonna turn prograde.
Wonderful.
And then, we're gonna burn slightly.
Periapsis at 37 kilometers.
Now, we're gonna bring it to 97.
Why?
I'll show you.
Fast forward like crazy now.
Oh my god, look at the debris around Kerbin.
It's been 13 days on this mission so far.
Whoa, even the moon!
Look!
That's so sick.
Dude, imagine what it's gonna be like when we go to planets further out.
We're talking, like, trips that last months?
Brother.
That's nuts.
Here we come.
So now we're at periapsis.
I will burn retrograde now to bring apoapsis down.
Maybe this is unnecessary.
But I do it anyway, because we got lots of fuel.
Actually, we don't even need to do that.
We can just sort of...
We can go into the atmosphere now.
We're kind of slow.
Periapsis.
Let's bring it down to 30 again.
That was a good number.
30.
That will bring us on the bright side, and it's gonna be a beautiful day on Kerbin.
Here we come!
Whoa!
Damn.
Okay, lock in!
Time for re-entry.
No more fucking around.
In fact, I'm gonna disengage.
Yep.
Disengage.
Three.
Two.
One.
Carson.
Wrong button, you idiot!
Thank you.
Classic Carson behavior, I'm telling you.
Every time.
After all the long hours of learning with Valentina, you know, he still hasn't got it down.
Wait, if I change this to...
Surface.
Okay, I guess we can just keep it there.
I wonder what's best, actually.
Maybe it doesn't matter.
It's gonna switch to Surface automatically at some point anyway.
Oh, right.
This one's gonna be activated when we come home.
Dude, we're gonna do the contract, and we're gonna get a million signs as well when we come home.
I feel like that...
Okay.
You know what?
When I was looking at the research and development page, and there were things costing, like, 200 signs and stuff, I thought, how am I ever gonna get that?
I think I understand now.
The amount of signs you get is, like, increasing...
Well, not exponentially, but close to it.
The further out you go, you know?
Which is kinda cool.
And the crazy thing is, so far, I've only been in the Kerbin system, if you think about it.
I've done Kerbin stuff, and we've been around, uh...
the moon, and also Minmus, which is another moon of Kerbin.
We haven't even landed on that yet.
Looking good.
Solid re-entry here.
Textbook.
We're gonna splash down in the ocean, it seems.
I actually like that.
Get our feet wet here.
Okay, time for chutes.
Deactivate SAS.
Next set of chutes.
Oh!
Oh my god, I'm so scared whenever that happens.
Phew.
Please don't crash on me now.
Whoa, this is looking very weird.
It's so...
I don't know...
Blue?
Hahaha!
Why are you blue?
Hey, what the fuck, actually?
I guess it's just very bright right now.
It's a weird view, isn't it?
Kinda beautiful.
Main chutes deploy, and two...
One...
There it is.
And we got so much science.
Is it...
Dude, it's like foggy as hell.
Look at this!
That's what that was!
Hold on.
Speed up time.
Man, this is the middle of nowhere.
I hope you brought GPS, Carson.
Otherwise, good luck.
And...
Splash down!
We have splash down!
Wonderful!
Bring home the science before anything goes wrong.
We don't want to drown now.
Oh...
172 science.
Oh my god, yes.
That is incredible.
Oh, look.
It's really foggy all over.
I guess it's... Dude, we have 600,000 money now.
We can upgrade.
Oh!
Max part supported 255.
What a jump, though.
Wait, from 30 to 255?
What?
That's a crazy jump.
Wait, what else can I get if I upgrade?
This is over a million!
Wait.
Unowned object tracking?
Mission control upgrade required for something.
I can't... Why can't I scroll?
Well, that's weird.
Dude, we should do this?
Flight planning?
What's that gonna do?
How do I plan?
Wait a minute.
I'm actually gonna look in the Gamepedia.
Space travel... Maneuvers?
Okay.
Wait.
Oh, maybe a flight interface?
Maneuver mode.
Maneuver mode!
Orbital information?
Oh, oh, no.
Never mind.
That's maneuver mode.
Maneuver mode.
Maneuver editor.
Oh!
When a maneuver node is selected on the map, or by interacting with the selection display buttons, the precision maneuver edit panel appears.
Post maneuver orbit... But is this what I got, though?
So... Yeah, I don't have this.
Or maybe I do now.
Warp to the next maneuver?
Wait, what?
Previous... Next maneuver.
Wait, hold on.
I need to read this.
When a maneuver node is selected on the map, or by interacting with the selection display buttons, the precision maneuver edit panel appears.
Post maneuver orbit information displays in the orbit information panel.
Oh.
Okay, so down here.
Okay.
Maneuver handles.
Use the handles to adjust maneuver direction by click, drag, or scroll.
The centered buttons adjust the time of the maneuver in the same way.
Scale slider.
Shows the current rate of change applied when using the handles.
But is this...
What I got, though?
It's not called flight planning.
Jackie.
What's up?
Come here.
Oh.
What's up, Jackie?
What's going on, huh?
I'm playing Kerbal Space Program.
I'm planning flights.
I love you.
Yeah.
There you go.
Maneuver tool.
Oh, wait.
Gives assistance, plotting, transfer, and intercept maneuvers.
Open the maneuver tool from the app bar for any craft in flight.
You'll need a level 3 tracking station when playing career.
I don't have that.
Select the part of the current craft's orbital plan that you want to create a maneuver in and choose your...
Okay, hold on.
Oh, it's...
Oh, so this is level 3.
Ah, maneuver tool.
You saw that?
Maneuver tool available.
Oh, that's expensive.
So what the hell is flight planning, though?
That, to me, sounds like I can, you know, sit at a drawing board or something and, like, plan the flight before I even start flying.
Which sounds amazing.
Is it from the tracking station, though?
Also, we have this thing.
Vessel.
That is Valentina's trash.
Terminate.
Gone.
We don't want no space trash here.
Wait a sec.
Orbit notes.
Oh, okay, so, yeah, this is what I unlocked last time.
Now I can see this.
This is actually exactly what I did today.
It's almost picture perfect, what I had, you know?
Sphere of influence change.
Where a maneuver has been planned.
This map tool is arguably the most important tool for getting your chosen destination.
With it, you plan the location, direction, and orientation of a burn.
A firing of the engines.
Simply left-click anywhere on your orbital path.
Right, but maybe this is what I have now.
Because I couldn't do that last time I did, or read this.
I guess I'll just have to try and fly.
Like, this, like, this is not even something I can see.
Dude, there's like a million things in this game.
It's crazy.
Flight activities.
Wait, invert SAS state while held?
Why would you want to do that?
You mean like, instead of going up, you go down?
That's weird.
RCS and trim.
Oh, yeah.
These are the keybinds that confused me the hell last time I read them on the cheat sheet.
I, K, J, and L.
So, this is RCS stuff.
Which is, what is it?
Control system something.
Fuck, what is it called?
It's called...
I don't know.
Something control system.
It's basically what you need to orient a spacecraft in space in a precise way, right?
For example, when you see the SpaceX launch and you see the little booster turn and stuff, you see these little squirts of air coming out.
It's not air, but it's basically like that, you know?
I guess this is going to be needed for the Clampatron or whatever.
The mouse in flight.
Double map.
Set focus.
Oh, oh, okay.
Double click.
Drag.
Eevee...
Wait, drag Eevee...
Oh, yeah, I figured that out.
Middle button.
Target vessel with camera.
Wait, pan and tilt camera?
You're kidding me.
I need to try that.
Open part menu.
Yeah, this one I know.
Okay.
Tracking station.
Hold on.
The current date, time controls, and a filter for vessel types.
All active flights and tracked space objects.
When selected, you will focus on that object and can manage it.
Right.
Okay, well, um...
Fine.
Cool.
What is the status now?
So we have the fucking moonstone.
So apparently we gotta go to a specific place here.
The polar lowlands...
I mean, okay.
That to me sounds like we gotta go to the pole and then go to the place that is low.
That sounds pretty self-explanatory.
Farsight crater could be a crater on the far side of the moon.
This one is a little more, uh, ambiguous.
But I don't know if it'll be obvious when I see the stone I need.
Explore Minimus.
Go on an orbital spacewalk near...
Look at all this money we're getting, man.
Just for orbiting?
Oh, this is easy as hell.
Are you kidding me?
We're taking that.
Holy shit.
Uh, what does it cost to upgrade this?
Oh my god.
That's so expensive.
What else can I upgrade?
I don't know if I want to upgrade that.
Kerbal EVAs can collect surface samples?
Wait, maybe I need this to even get the moon rock, anyway.
Resource transfer available!
Oh!
I see...
Ha!
Unlimited now!
That's funny.
I actually didn't even realize there still was a limit to the weight.
I guess I haven't hit that limit yet.
Max active contracts from 7 to unlimited.
Wait, are you saying I have 7 now?
That's not true.
Oh my god!
It is true!
Wait, I thought I could only have 2!
Am I...
I'm losing my mind?
When the hell did I gain this ability?
I'm losing my mind.
Well, I need this then.
Do we land on...
Dude, are we going for a landing immediately?
That's kind of crazy.
Wait, we have science!
I almost forgot!
I know what I'm getting.
Was it that one?
No.
It was the heat shield.
Oh, maybe it was this one.
We need this.
Landing.
Boom.
Oh, we almost have enough for another round.
That's too bad.
I guess I can get this.
But do I want that?
No, I don't want that.
Fuck that.
Boo.
Nobody cares about that.
Oh man, oh man.
We gotta stop, though.
We gotta take a break here.
It's too much of the good stuff.
As they say.
Whew!
What's up, guys?
What did you think of that?
I could watch forever?
I could play forever, too.
Dude, we're at five hours again.
What the fuck is with this game?
This game is so good.
This game is a freaking masterpiece.
And it still feels like I've just scratched the surface.
Right?
It's insane.
This game keeps getting better somehow.
How is it possible?
Well, okay.
I do love space.
But, man, this game just gives you that feeling of being in space.
Even though I'm talking as if I've been in space.
I have not been to space.
But, even then, you know, I feel like I'm in space.
And you know what?
It's giving me that sort of, uh...
Some kind of dread, almost.
Like, when you're out there and you're just in the middle of nothing, you know?
And at the mercy of gravity and the distances involved, it's just insane.
What a feeling.
It's definitely, like, a weird kind of scary.
But in a really cool way.
Such a great atmosphere.
Is there an easy way to play this game with the same mods as you?
I put the mod list on my YouTube description.
I mean, other than my own little, uh...
Self-concocted mods, right?
Like the music edition and...
The flag fix, not...
Stuff like that, you know?
Other than that, it's gonna look precisely the same.
What did you mean when you said you want to see Kerbal burning?
I meant that I want to see how the game handles a situation...
Where you take a Kerbal...
Outside of a spaceship...
And let that Kerbal burn up in the atmosphere.
It's a morbid curiosity, that's all.
And obviously, we're only gonna do it to someone who's a troublemaker...
In the Kerbal society.
So, I'm just like...
Disgusting.
I mean...
You got me, it is...
Yeah.
I'm a disgusting person.
Stop killing them on purpose?
I haven't done it yet.
It's just, you know...
Thoughts that are intruding.
Intrusive thoughts.
What the hell, dude?
Listen, I'm only gonna do it to the war criminals.
If there's a Kerbal out there, you know...
Who ate a little more than his share of cake...
In the break room...
Then...
He will burn.
Because that is a crime that...
Just is unacceptable in Kerbal society.
I get so much anxiety when you go into first person view close to the moon.
Really?
I love first person.
I think it's...
Yeah, I mean...
It does give me a little bit of the same.
But yeah, it's amazing.
It's just a great feeling.
I mean, you can suggest mods for me.
Sure.
I'm modding this game like crazy right now.
If you got something good, I'll take a look at it.
Let me know.
I mean, as long as it's, you know...
Just mostly graphical stuff.
Like bug fixes or, you know, stuff like that or...
Better contract packs.
It's the...
But here's the thing.
That sounds to me like a gameplay change.
I'm afraid that will somehow make it easier or harder or...
It's gonna change the game, isn't it?
There's a mod for more instruments for IVA.
Raster...
Prop monitor.
I've actually seen that one.
On, uh...
Seacan.
And I saw a screenshot of it.
And I was like, what the fuck, bro?
This doesn't look...
Like something I could manage.
It looks crazy.
Yeah, it's called raster prop monitor.
I've seen that one.
So I don't know if I want something like that.
That sounds a little crazy to me.
You would love free IVA?
Okay, what is that one?
Free IVA.
Allows you to get out of your seat...
And move around your ship.
Really?
Is it janky, though?
Or is it, like, perfectly made?
Because if it's super janky...
I don't know if I want to.
Like, how would you even walk around?
Like, there's no space to walk around.
It's good?
Okay.
Maybe I'll check it out.
I'll do a quick test, maybe.
See if I like it.
You can get first person in EVA with Through the Eyes of a Kerbal.
Ooh, okay.
Maybe I'll check that one out.
That sounds good.
Through the Eyes of a Kerbal.
I like that the mod name is so descriptive, too.
It's exactly what it is.
Wait, I hope it's like a view from inside the helmet, too.
Okay, I will give that a look.
I'm writing it down.
That's a great suggestion there.
That sounds great.
Through the Eyes of a Kerbal.
I'm gonna write Free IVA, too.
Anything else you got?
Graphically, or...
Something like that?
Check out Space Potato Visual Enhancements.
What's that?
Hold on.
You mentioned Potato.
I'm intrigued.
Oh, it's just the guy's name called Space Potato.
Oh, it's like adding extra clouds and stuff, it seems.
Surface Ambience.
Okay.
Maybe I'll check it out.
Is it gonna work well, though, with the other mods that I have?
Because, you know, apparently there's a lot of...
Like, just getting some of this to work was like a pain.
Because I'm also not, you know...
It won't?
Wait, are you saying it's not gonna be compatible?
Or are you saying...
Wait, what are you saying?
Chatterer adds radio chatting between Kerbonauts and ground controls.
Ooh, that sounds really cool!
Wait, hold on.
Chatterer.
Okay, hold on.
That sounds amazing.
I will investigate that for sure.
Wait.
Wait, really?
I hope it's gonna be...
Like, the Sims, you know, where you don't really know what they're saying.
I hope it's not gonna be actual people speaking, like...
It's...
Yeah.
It's gotta fit the...
The silliness, you know what I mean?
Sul Sul.
Exactly, that one.
Yeah, it's gibberish.
Great.
Okay, I will take it out.
That actually sounds so good.
That's like one of those things where you hear it, you're like...
Man, I didn't know I wanted this until I heard it, you know?
It's real astronomer talk, but garbled.
Do you mean astronaut talk?
D-E-I-V-A, okay.
What's that?
Wait, are you...
Do you mean the D-E-I-V-A extension?
It's the only one I'm seeing.
Bro, what the...
I'm looking at a screenshot, and it looks like something that just multiplied the complexity of the game by a million-fold.
I'm not sure that's something that I need.
But I am judging just from a screenshot.
I don't know about that.
It doesn't?
Hmm.
Dude, are you seeing the screenshot I'm seeing?
Like, come on.
There's like a million buttons.
It looks a little too realistic for the silliness that is the Kerbal universe, doesn't it?
It's all the usual instruments, but in IV-V-A.
Oh, okay.
Okay, hold on, you have my attention.
Okay, I'll write it on the list.
I'll check it out, I'll check it out.
Wait, I need to just copy the name here.
Guys, I need to ask, what was your reaction to, uh...
What did you think of my attempt at trying to rescue Valentina today?
Because that was like a car crash in slow motion at this point.
Wasn't that crazy?
I can't believe we lost Valentina, man.
Oh, it was so bad.
You pointed it prograde when it was already retro?
Nah, no, no, no.
Nope.
I didn't.
I am 100% sure I didn't.
Because you have to remember, it's going to stay the same orientation going around Kerban.
Right?
So if it was retro on one side, it's not going to be retro on the other side.
You did exactly 180?
Well, exactly.
That's the point.
I wanted to do 180.
Unless you meant to say 360 just now.
Yeah.
I mean, in hindsight, I knew what I should have done.
I even thought about it.
I even said it out loud.
What I should have done was try to get into a stable orbit with just my Kerbal.
Using my thrusters.
Because you actually have some power in those.
I mean, you can get up to quite a bit of meters per second with that.
So all I should have done is just go into a stable orbit with her.
And then come rescue her later.
I even thought about it.
But I fucking hubris took over, man.
I thought I had it.
And I thought it was such a cool attempt, you know?
I wanted to go for it.
That's the Valentina way, man.
She's a brave old Kerbal.
What's the mod for Parachute Physics?
That's part of my own mod.
I just call it my tweaks.
Add some funny little things, you know?
If you had completely burned through the remaining step, you would have had enough electricity for SAS.
Yeah, I realized later on, right?
That that was...
I mean, I didn't really know at the time.
You have to remember, like...
I didn't realize that was what was happening at the time.
Yeah, it's fully custom.
It's just asking Opus 5.5, Hey, make it, like, fold and, you know, bend with the wind and have it, you know, fall down realistically.
Boom.
Done.
So awesome, man.
We're entering an age where you just do amazing things with your games, you know?
I love it.
Do you have community fixes?
I do.
I do have it.
I'm not sure what it fixes, but I like something being fixed.
So I have it.
I think time warping on the moon with your SAS still on is what drained the battery.
Oh, yeah, because I was constantly adjusting all the time.
It makes sense.
I mean, that's what I thought as well, you know?
I had it on too much.
I was using it too much.
Okay, guys, it's time for me to eat.
I am hungry.
Thank you for watching.
This was a great stream.
As always, this game is, like...
This series may become one of my favorites I've done.
I'm not even kidding.
Like, if this keeps up...
Holy shit.
Fucking 10 out of 10 so far on this.
Damn.
I'll see you around.
Thanks for sticking around.
Bye-bye.